<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/?t=c951724f17882c293435a61d10002d8b" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>Serving the Technologist for more than a decade. IT news, reviews, and analysis.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 22:23:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>For the first time in decades, Congress seems interested space-based solar power</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947937</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2023/06/for-the-first-time-in-decades-congress-seems-interested-space-based-solar-power/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 22:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space based solar power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["We already know from early research that it is possible."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/MAPLE_rec1.original-800x295.jpg" alt="A photo taken of the first space-borne prototype from Caltech's Space Solar Power Project. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/MAPLE_rec1.original.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="574" data-width="1556">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A photo taken of the first space-borne prototype from Caltech's Space Solar Power Project.  (credit: SSPP)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>As far as legislative moments go, the passage of a minor amendment to an innocuous US House resolution on Wednesday was not exactly groundbreaking. But for space exploration enthusiasts, <a href="https://republicans-science.house.gov/_cache/files/d/b/dbd4efc2-e2c0-4f95-9106-6773d8158bb5/565725B24E244E9FEF0193CC0F86FB21.h.r.-2988-amendment-008-mullin.pdf">the amendment offered</a> by US Rep. Kevin Mullin, D-Calif., was kind of a big deal.</p>
<p>That's because, for the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/GPO-CRECB-1978-pt5/pdf/GPO-CRECB-1978-pt5-6-1.pdf">first time since the 1970s</a>, the idea of space-based solar power has been addressed legislatively by the US Congress.</p>
<p>"Although the technology to gather solar energy in space and send it to the surface as electricity is not yet commercially viable at scale, we already know from early research that it is possible," Mullin said <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eIGXFnXP1W4&amp;t=1680s">during a meeting</a> of the Science, Space, and Technology Committee on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Mullin was seeking to amend House Resolution 2988, a bill instructing NASA and the US Department of Energy to collaborate on key areas of research and development, including propulsion, artificial intelligence, astrophysics, Earth science, and quantum computing. He sought to add space-based solar power to the list. The amendment passed overwhelmingly by a bipartisan committee vote.</p>

<p>In his remarks, Mullin noted that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2022/08/european-space-chief-says-continent-will-lead-in-space-based-solar-power/">Europe</a>, Japan, China, and the United Kingdom are all studying the technology and considering in-space demonstrations. And in the United States, the California Institute of Technology <a href="https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/in-a-first-caltechs-space-solar-power-demonstrator-wirelessly-transmits-power-in-space">recently demonstrated</a> the ability to wirelessly transmit power in space and beam detectable power back to Earth.</p>
<p>"A lot of the technology that once made this source of energy the work of science fiction is now much cheaper, and easier to deploy than ever, putting it within reach," Mullin said. "But it's not inevitable that this promising research will become feasible at scale. There are still science and engineering hurdles to overcome. And if the United States doesn't do it, we know our friends and global competitors will."</p>
<h2>Sending a message</h2>
<p>The legislation, with Mullin's amendment now attached, should be voted on by the committee on Thursday. If passed, as expected, it will likely become part of a House authorization bill later this year.</p>
<p>The House resolution carries no funding for these initiatives, and it's not like NASA and the Department of Energy will drop everything tomorrow and start working on space-based solar power. But the resolution signals the intent of Congress to NASA and the Department of Energy that it is interested in seeing some movement on this topic. This could presage eventual funding.</p>
<p>Before its passage, the amendment was supported by several space advocacy groups, including the Alliance for Space Development, Space Frontier Foundation, and National Space Society. "This is the first time since the 1970s that the idea of space solar power has been addressed in legislation," said Jonathan Dagle, a policy manager for the National Space Society. He characterized the amendment as "a small but significant victory."</p>
<p>NASA could do with a little prodding on the subject. Last year, at the International Space Development Conference, <a href="https://spacenews.com/nasa-to-reexamine-space-based-solar-power/">a NASA official said</a> the agency had begun a short-term study evaluating the prospects of space-based solar power. This was the agency's first real look at the subject in about two decades. However, that study has not been released publicly, as there were apparently some policy concerns about the first draft. The revised study <a href="https://twitter.com/davehuntsman/status/1669093774704648192">may finally be released</a> in late June or July.</p>
<p>Part of the renewed interest in solar power from space is due to the expansion of launch capabilities, particularly the potential of SpaceX's Starship launch vehicle to carry large payloads into orbit with a reusable first and second stage. This dramatic improvement in launch costs and upmass could help to address some of the economic concerns with the technology—namely that it is often more efficient to put solar panels in the desert than in space.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947937&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/space/2023/06/for-the-first-time-in-decades-congress-seems-interested-space-based-solar-power/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ancient Egyptian followers of a deity called Bes may have used hallucinogens</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947818</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/ancient-egyptian-followers-of-a-deity-called-bes-may-have-used-hallucinogens/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 21:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hallucinogens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychotropics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue water lily acts as a sedative, while Syrian rue induces dream-like visions.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/BesVase1CROP-800x541.jpg" alt="Drinking vessel in shape of Bes head"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/BesVase1CROP.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="811" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> An Egyptian drinking vessel in the shape of Bes head contained traces of Syrian rue and blue water lily, among other compounds. (credit: Tampa Museum of Art, Florida)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>An ancient Egyptian vase in the shape of the deity <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bes">Bes</a> showed traces of chemical plant compounds known to produce hallucinations, according to a <a href="https://www.researchsquare.com/article/rs-3000218/v1">recent preprint</a> posted to Research Square. The authors suggest that members of the cult of Bes may have consumed a special cocktail containing the compounds to induce altered states of consciousness.</p>
<p>There is ample evidence that humans in many cultures throughout history used various hallucinogenic substances in religious ceremonies or shamanic rituals. That includes not just ancient Egypt but also ancient Greek, Vedic, Maya, Inca, and Aztec cultures. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urarina">Urarina</a> people who live in the Peruvian Amazon Basin still use a psychoactive brew called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayahuasca">ayahuasca</a> in their rituals, and Westerners seeking their own brand of enlightenment have also been known to participate.</p>
<p>Lacing the beer served at their feasts with hallucinogens may have helped an ancient Peruvian people known as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wari_culture" data-uri="c892a87dd8d7668938e6dc9fb6835e24">Wari</a> forge political alliances and expand their empire, according to a <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/antiquity/article/abs/hallucinogens-alcohol-and-shifting-leadership-strategies-in-the-ancient-peruvian-andes/15030A62A428B74805BADF7DB4137298">2022 study</a>. As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2022/01/ancient-peruvians-partied-hard-spiked-their-beer-with-hallucinogens-to-win-friends/">previously reported</a>, the use of hallucinogens, particularly a substance derived from the seeds of the vilca tree, was common in the region during the so-called Middle Horizon period, when the Wari empire thrived. </p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anadenanthera_colubrina" data-uri="3a6df6d3c2d96f72fb0cb9f5d242f8a1">Vilca</a> typically grows in the dry tropical forests in the region. The trees produce long legumes filled with thin seeds. The seeds, bark, and other parts of the tree all contain <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N,N-Dimethyltryptamine" data-uri="a46edd3713c55d191a6f1646e5f132b7">DMT</a>, a well-known psychedelic substance that is also found in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayahuasca" data-uri="00a69242c8e3de25bae5c37a10aa5b44">ayahuasca brews,</a> but the primary active ingredient is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bufotenin" data-uri="2020545207fd054347a59f508a981adf">bufotenine</a>. It was usually smoked, ingested in the form of snuff, or used as an enema. A 4,000-year-old pipe laced with bufotenine residue and related paraphernalia was found in an Incan cave in Argentina in 1999—the oldest archaeological evidence to date for using vilca in South America.</p>
<p>There is also evidence from historical accounts that a juice or tea derived from vilca seeds was sometimes added to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicha" data-uri="c21a2360adabd3716aa92dc9f9e606ef">chicha</a>, a fermented beverage made from maize or the fruits of the molle tree native to Peru. And people of the state of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tiwanaku">Tiwanaku</a> were known to mix such hallucinogens with alcohol, specifically maize beer. There are monoliths depicting figures holding a drinking cup in one hand and a snuff tray in another, and smoking or inhaling vilca was part of a long-standing ritual tradition to foster personal spiritual journeys.</p>
<p>For this latest work, Davide Tanasi of the University of South Florida and his co-authors analyzed an Egyptian ritual vase in the shape of Bes dating back to the second century BCE—known as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ptolemaic_Kingdom">Ptolemaic period</a>—in the collection of the Tampa Museum of Art in Florida. Bes was a popular deity believed to confer protection on households, especially mothers and children. So unlike most other Egyptian deities, images of Bes were quite common in Egyptian homes. There were even special chambers built to honor Bes and his wife Beset at the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saqqara">Saqqara</a> site near Cairo, which Egyptologists think could have been used for fertility or healing rituals, although their exact purpose is not certain.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/BesVase1.jpg"><img alt='Various examples of Bes mugs.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/BesVase1-640x575.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/BesVase1.jpg 2x" alt='Various examples of Bes mugs.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/BesVase1.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Various examples of Bes mugs.</a> (credit: D. Tanasi et al., 2023)</p></div>
<p>Many ceramic vases or similar vessels representing Bes have been found and now populate museums and private collections around the world. Most hypotheses about what the vessels may have held, and the purposes for which they were used, are based on mythological sources. Scholars have suggested they held sacred water, milk, wine, beer, kohl, perfume, or medicinal potions, but few have been tested for traces of organic compounds. One <a href="https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Water%2C-milk%2C-beer-and-wine-for-the-living-and-the-%3A-Kaiser/15549228ac3223af9b4613998e9566c0d486972e">2004 study</a> looked for residues of animal proteins in 23 Bes vases, but the DNA analysis turned up just four positive results due to protein degradation and other challenges.</p>
<p>So the Tampa Museum of Art's Bes vase offered an opportunity to address how such a vase might have been used in Bes-related rituals, per the authors. The museum acquired the vase in 1984 from a private collection; it had been purchased from a gallery in Cairo in 1960. After collecting sample residues from the vessel, Tanasi <em>et al</em>. applied various techniques—including proteomic and genetic analyses and synchrotron radiation-based Fourier-transform infrared microspectroscopy—to characterize the residues.</p>
<p>Among the more intriguing results was the presence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peganum_harmala">Syrian rue</a> (<em>Peganum harmala</em>), whose seeds are known to have hallucinogenic properties that can induce dream-like visions, per the authors, thanks to its production of the alkaloids harmine and harmaline. There were also traces of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nymphaea_nouchali_var._caerulea">blue water lily</a> (<em>Nymphaea cerulea</em>), which contains a psychoactive alkaloid that acts as a sedative; it's one of several candidate plants that scholars believe might be the fruit of the lotus tree described in Homer's <em>Odyssey</em>. Both were known to the Egyptians, and the authors concluded that these two plants "were deliberately used as sources of psychoactive substances for ritual purposes."</p>
<p>In addition, Tanasi <em>et al</em>. identified traces of a fermented alcoholic concoction containing yeasts, wheat, sesame seeds, fruit (possibly grapes), honey, and, um, "human fluids": possibly breast milk, oral or vaginal mucus, and blood. (The traces of human skin were dismissed as likely contamination.) "In light of our results, it would be possible to infer that this Bes vase was used for some sort of ritual of re-enactment of what happened in a significant event in Egyptian myth," the authors wrote. That would be the Myth of the Solar Eye, in which Bes served the goddess <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hathor">Hathor</a> an alcoholic drink spiked with a plant-based drug to make her fall into a deep sleep and forget about exacting vengeance.</p>
<p>Also, graffiti refers to Bes as the "giver of oracles" and the "giver of dreams," and one known ritual of the cult involved sleeping in the Saqqara chambers in hopes of having prophetic dreams. The compounds identified in this particular Bes vase would certainly have aided in that objective. However, the authors cautioned that Egyptian belief systems and ritual practices were very complex, and their findings may only apply to this particular vessel. Performing similar analysis on other examples of Bes vases would further enhance our understanding of the purpose of these intriguing artifacts.</p>
<p>DOI: Research Square, 2023. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3000218/v1">10.21203/rs.3.rs-3000218/v1</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947818&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/ancient-egyptian-followers-of-a-deity-called-bes-may-have-used-hallucinogens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Comcast and Charter are making a streaming box for self-loathing cord-cutters</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947856</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/comcast-and-charter-are-making-a-streaming-box-for-self-loathing-cord-cutters/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Purdy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 21:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charter spectrum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Xumo Box will bring typical apps, plus ad-supported semi-channels, to TVs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/flex-april-2022-2523.jpg" alt="Xfinity Flex box in front of a row of video images"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/flex-april-2022-2523.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="6667" data-width="10417">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Xfinity's Flex box is likely the model for the Xumo Box, a streaming device to be sold at Walmart later this year. (credit: Xfinity/Comcast/Charter)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>There are an overwhelming number of choices right now for watching streaming media on your TV. Most TVs have a system built in, often Roku, Google, or Samsung. Standalone boxes from Roku, Apple, Google, and Amazon run the third-party market, and smaller vendors offer remarkably cheap Android-based boxes online and at discount retailers.</p>
<p>But—wait—that's not all. Now Comcast and Charter, the largest and second-largest cable companies in the US, have their own HDMI-box offering. If you've always wanted a box that is stuffed full of "free" ad-stuffed, pseudo-streaming channels, doesn't have the app stores or mirroring capabilities of the major brands, and helps major cable companies regain market position and recoup revenue lost to cord-cutters like you, <a href="https://cordcuttersnews.com/comcast-spectrum-plan-to-take-on-roku-amazon-by-selling-a-streaming-player-at-walmart/?tag=reviewgeek-20&amp;asc_refurl=https://www.reviewgeek.com/155350/these-cable-companies-are-teaming-up-to-sell-a-streaming-box-at-walmart/\">say hello to the Xumo Box</a>.</p>
<p>Xumo is the name of <a href="https://play.xumo.com/live-guide/cbs-news">Comcast's free streaming service</a>, purchased by the company in 2020. It's the kind that looks like a cable channel guide and has an endless loop of pre-selected game shows, reality TV, crime procedurals, and other ready-to-license material akin to Pluto and Freevee. Xumo is a big part of <a href="https://www.xfinity.com/learn/flex?cjevent=75804f2a0aed11ee8109524d0a82b832&amp;cjdata=MXxOfDB8WXww">Flex</a>, the streaming box Comcast's Xfinity service offers to customers who don't want a traditional TV plan.</p>
<p>The Xumo Box is a rebranded Flex, but will be sold in Walmart and other stores in late 2023, as <a href="https://cordcuttersnews.com/comcast-spectrum-plan-to-take-on-roku-amazon-by-selling-a-streaming-player-at-walmart/?tag=reviewgeek-20&amp;asc_refurl=https://www.reviewgeek.com/155350/these-cable-companies-are-teaming-up-to-sell-a-streaming-box-at-walmart/">reported by Cord Cutters</a>. It seems likely to be offered to both Comcast and Charter Spectrum customers, given that Charter <a href="https://corporate.comcast.com/press/releases/comcast-charter-flex-nationwide-streaming-xclass-tv">put $900 million into a joint venture</a> to produce "a variety of branded 4K streaming devices and smart TVs." Cord Cutters suggests the pricing to be "very competitive" with Roku and Fire TV boxes, which can be had for as low as $25 while on sale.</p>
<p>The existence of a retail box comes shortly after the Xumo venture announced it would provide its free (i.e., ad-supported) <a href="https://thedesk.net/2023/06/xumo-power-free-ad-supported-tcl-channels/">streaming channels on TCL smart TVs</a>. Meanwhile, the Xumo venture aims to also provide its own TVs at some point.</p>
<p>From reading reviews of the Flex over the last few years, it has picked up <a href="https://www.xfinity.com/learn/digital-cable-tv/streaming-services?INTCMP=FlexLearn_Flex_ExploreAppsFlex_Flex">many more services</a> while aggressively pushing its Xumo-centric "Free to you" section. Otherwise, it has reportedly decent voice control and a fairly standard "rows of squares" interface. Each streaming service is added by Xfinity, however, rather than being available in an app store akin to what Apple, Google, Amazon, or Roku provide.</p>
<p>Comcast and Charter aren't likely getting into the streaming hardware business because they're eager to spend hundreds of millions of dollars getting to fifth place. Rather, they've noticed that nearly a third of TVs sold in the U.S. are running Roku's software, that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/01/this-spring-roku-will-finally-start-shipping-its-own-tvs/">Roku is making its own TVs</a>, and they see a lot of ads, and customer data, left on the table. Comcast and Charter <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/08/charter-loses-home-internet-customers-blames-end-of-covid-subsidy-program/">failed to add more Internet customers in mid-2022</a>, a rare result that could have both companies considering revenue diversification.</p>
<p>Time will tell if those needing a new streaming box will turn to a new box backed by companies with <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/05/comcast-time-warner-cable-still-have-the-angriest-customers-survey-finds/">historically tricky brands</a>.</p>
<p><em>The Advance/Newhouse Partnership, which owns 12.4 percent of Charter, is part of Advance Publications. Advance Publications owns Condé Nast, which owns Ars Technica.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947856&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/comcast-and-charter-are-making-a-streaming-box-for-self-loathing-cord-cutters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Body mass index gets smack down: AMA calls out harms and “racist exclusion”</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947915</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2023/06/american-medical-assoc-blasts-bmi-for-historical-harm-racist-exclusion/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 21:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[body mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cardiovascular disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lean mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obesity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947915</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The massive medical group says it has some value, but called for a better standard.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-875568858-800x496.jpeg" alt="Body mass index gets smack down: AMA calls out harms and “racist exclusion”"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-875568858-scaled.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1587" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/the-hospital-j-m-de-los-rios-a-weighing-scale-in-the-news-photo/875568858?adppopup=true">Getty | Thierry Monasse</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Body mass index has for decades been used as a shorthand for assessing body fat and weight-related health risks. But for about just as long, critics have noted the simple calculation is laden with problems; BMI doesn’t actually measure fat mass, account for its distribution, or how those differ by age, gender, ethnicity, race, and how those differences affect health risks. Calculations and cutoffs are largely based on past generations of non-Hispanic white people. And BMI classifications mislead people on their individual risks of disease and death, and can lead to substandard care for eating disorders.</p>
<p>Now, it seems the hefty criticism has finally reached a critical mass. During the annual meeting of the American Medical Association (AMA) this week in Chicago, physicians and medical students voted to adopt <a href="https://www.ama-assn.org/system/files/a23-refcomm-d-annotated.pdf">a strongly worded policy</a> acknowledging the calculation's "significant limitations" and "historical harms," including "racist exclusion." While the massive medical group acknowledged that BMI remains useful for population-level trends and associations, the policy called for doctors to become familiar with the calculation's problems and explore alternative measurements for diagnosing obesity and assessing health risks.</p>
<p>"There are numerous concerns with the way BMI has been used to measure body fat and diagnose obesity, yet some physicians find it to be a helpful measure in certain scenarios," AMA Immediate Past President Jack Resneck, Jr., said in <a href="https://www.ama-assn.org/press-center/press-releases/ama-adopts-new-public-health-policies-improve-health-nation-6">a statement</a>.  "It is important for physicians to understand the benefits and limitations of using BMI in clinical settings to determine the best care for their patients."</p>
<h2>History</h2>
<p>The shift will likely inspire cheers from critics, who have been increasing for decades. Even before the rise of BMI— aka the Quetelet Index as it was called in the 1970s—medical researchers had realized that simple features like leg length, bone mass, and body frame influenced weight-to-height ratios.</p>
<p>BMI is a simple calculation of weight in kilograms divided by height in meters squared. In 1993, an expert advisory committee for the World Health Organization came up with four BMI-based weight categories: underweight (below 20), normal weight (20 to 24.9), overweight (25 to 29.9), and obese (30 and up). In the US then, the National Institutes of Health considered the threshold for overweight to be a BMI of 27.8  for men or 27.3 for women. Anything under those cutoffs was "normal." This was based on an 85 percent cutoff point from data in a large national NIH survey. But in 1998, the NIH lowered the cutoff to 25, aligning with WHO categories. And overnight, millions of Americans went from having normal weight to overweight. <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/healthyweight/assessing/bmi/adult_bmi/index.html#InterpretedAdults">That cutoff is still used</a>.</p>
<p>BMI is a simple, easy-to-obtain number that has strong, established associations with body fatness, morbidity, and mortality data. But on an individual level, it's loaded with limitations. For one, it doesn't actually measure body fat mass—it can't distinguish lean mass from fat.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Disadvantages</h2>
<p>In <a href="https://www.ama-assn.org/system/files/a23-handbook-refcom-d.pdf">a report prepared by an AMA council</a> before the vote, council members noted that updated data from a national NIH survey compared BMI to body fat percentages based on bioelectric impedance. In subjects all with a BMI of 25, the percent of body fat in men varied between 14 percent and 35 percent, and in women, it varied between 26 percent and 43 percent, the report noted. Based on the NIH's criteria for defining obesity based on percent of body fat, subjects with the same BMI—which was at the cutoff for overweight—were associated with a body fat mass that varied between "low normal" to "obese."</p>
<p>BMI also doesn't account for fat distribution and a person's life stage. For decades, researchers have noted that the accumulation of fat in the upper part of the body ("apple-shaped" body) is linked to higher risks of diseases, like coronary heart disease and diabetes, compared to when fat accumulates in the lower body ("pear-shaped" body). Hormonal changes in puberty may be linked to some fat distribution differences. For instance, females generally develop fat stores around their pelvis and thigh during puberty, which is not seen in males, who develop a relatively larger amount of lean mass during puberty. And as women age, they tend to lose bone and muscle mass. Thus, as the AMA report notes, a 65-year-old woman who weighs the same as she did when she was 25 will actually have a higher percentage of body fat than she has in the past.</p>
<p>Beyond gender, racial and ethnic minorities also have different weight-related health risks. For example, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16801583/">a 2006 study</a> found that Asian women had more than double the risk of developing diabetes than white women who had the same BMI. Other studies have also noted that Asians have higher risks of cardiovascular disease at the same BMIs as white Europeans. One possible explanation is differences in fat mass. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12164465/">A 2002 study</a> found that, when compared to white Europeans of the same BMI, Asian people have 3 percent to 5 percent higher body fat. In contrast, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17342075/">a 2007 study</a> suggested that Black women have higher lean mass than white women.</p>
<p>The AMA report also noted that BMI doesn't account for other factors that can significantly affect health, such as family history of disease, genetic factors, smoking, excessive alcohol use, mental health, stability of body weight, medication-induced obesity, and a person's occupation. The simple BMI-based cutoffs for underweight can miss eating disorders, and the AMA notes that an "overemphasis of bodily thinness is as deleterious to one's physical and mental health as obesity."</p>
<h2>Alternatives</h2>
<p>To move away from the harms and limitations of BMI, the AMA calls for researchers to become familiar with alternative ways of assessing fat and research these as potential new standards. These include: abdominal circumference measurements; waist-to-hip ratio; skinfold measurements; an empirical mathematical model called the Visceral Adiposity Index; a linear equation for the relative fat mass, which is based on a height-to-waist ratio; underwater weighting to look at body density (hydrostatic weighting); and air displacement plethysmography (aka Bod Pod).</p>
<p>There's also bioelectrical impedance, which models the body as five cylinders of mass (the trunk and four limbs) and estimates body fat mass. Last, there's a variety of imaging methods including dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA), computed tomography (CT) scans, and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). The combination of CT and MRI scans is currently considered the gold standard for body composition analysis, the AMA notes.</p>
<p>In all, the AMA's new policy acknowledges "the significant limitations associated with the widespread use of BMI in clinical settings and suggests its use be in a conjunction with other valid measures of risk."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947915&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/health/2023/06/american-medical-assoc-blasts-bmi-for-historical-harm-racist-exclusion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Report: Microsoft launched Bing chatbot despite OpenAI warning it wasn’t ready</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947867</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/report-microsoft-launched-bing-chatbot-despite-openai-warning-it-wasnt-ready/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 20:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChatGPT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPT-4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satya Nadella]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sydney]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft execs purportedly had "misgivings about the timing of ChatGPT’s launch."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-1247508403-800x534.jpg" alt="Report: Microsoft launched Bing chatbot despite OpenAI warning it wasn’t ready"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-1247508403.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/chatgpt-website-displayed-on-a-laptop-screen-and-microsoft-news-photo/1247508403">NurPhoto / Contributor | NurPhoto</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Tension and confusion have made the partnership between Microsoft and OpenAI "awkward," people familiar with the matter revealed in a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/microsoft-and-openai-forge-awkward-partnership-as-techs-new-power-couple-3092de51">Wall Street Journal report</a> today.</p>
<p>Not only has this tension and confusion extended to Microsoft's internal AI team—which apparently is dealing with budget cuts and limited access to OpenAI technology—but sources said it also clouded Microsoft's controversial <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/02/microsoft-announces-ai-powered-bing-search-and-edge-browser/">rollout of AI-powered Bing search</a> last February. At that time, Bing was found to be <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/02/ai-powered-bing-chat-spills-its-secrets-via-prompt-injection-attack/">vulnerable to prompt injection attacks</a> revealing company secrets and providing sometimes inaccurate and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/02/ai-powered-bing-chat-loses-its-mind-when-fed-ars-technica-article/">truly unhinged responses to user prompts</a>.</p>
<p>According to WSJ, OpenAI warned Microsoft "about the perils of rushing to integrate OpenAI’s technology without training it more" and "suggested Microsoft move slower on integrating its AI technology with Bing." A top concern for OpenAI was that Bing's chatbot, Sydney, might give inaccurate or unhinged responses, but this early warning seemingly was easily ignored by Microsoft.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/microsofts-satya-nadella-is-betting-everything-on-ai/">Wired interview</a> published today, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella suggested that any hiccups with Sydney at first were just part of Microsoft's plan for training the chatbot to respond to real-world prompts that couldn't be tested in a lab.</p>
<p>"We did not launch Sydney with GPT-4 the first day I saw it, because we had to do a lot of work to build a safety harness," Nadella told Wired. "But we also knew we couldn't do all the alignment in the lab. To align an AI model with the world, you have to align it in the world and not in some simulation."</p>
<p>So that's partly why Microsoft rushed ahead anyway, but sources told WSJ that the rush was also partly due to Microsoft executives who had "misgivings about the timing of ChatGPT’s launch last fall."</p>
<p>Because OpenAI started ChatGPT's public testing while Microsoft was still working on integrating OpenAI tech into Bing, tension seemingly spiked between the partners, who also stood as rivals in an AI race to capture the world's attention.</p>
<p>As ChatGPT's success grew, some Microsoft employees raised concerns that ChatGPT was stealing Bing's "thunder," WSJ reported. Others sensibly posited that Microsoft could learn valuable lessons ahead of Bing's rollout from ChatGPT's early public testing. While Microsoft watched its partner grow ever more popular by the minute, it's easy to see why the company placed more urgency on AI-powered Bing's release. Public interest in the technology was there, and Microsoft wanted to be a bigger part of the conversation.</p>
<p>Of course, ChatGPT ultimately won the AI race, instantly attracting the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/02/chatgpt-sets-record-for-fastest-growing-user-base-in-history-report-says/">fastest-growing user base in history</a>. Meanwhile, "the new Bing," released a month later, "has yet to come close to the breakout success of ChatGPT," WSJ reported. Citing data from analytics firm YipitData, WSJ reported that ChatGPT "has nearly double the average number of daily search sessions as Bing search does." YipitData reported that ChatGPT has reached 200 million monthly users, while <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/03/ai-powered-chat-helps-bing-make-a-small-dent-in-googles-search-hegemony/">Bing hit 100 million daily active users</a> in March.</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/04/why-ai-chatbots-are-the-ultimate-bs-machines-and-how-people-hope-to-fix-them/4/">ChatGPT and Bing were later criticized</a> for launching chatbots guilty of making up stuff, lying, and other issues that many users didn't expect to encounter. OpenAI is still looking for ways to limit chatbots' so-called "hallucinations," <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/05/31/openai-is-pursuing-a-new-way-to-fight-ai-hallucinations.html">CNBC reported</a> in May. In February, Microsoft had to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/02/microsoft-lobotomized-ai-powered-bing-chat-and-its-fans-arent-happy/">update Bing to limit long conversations </a>until the company could find a better solution. Even after working on the issue for months, though, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/13/23759348/openai-microsoft-bing-ai-warning-gpt-4">The Verge reported</a> that—while Bing may respond with fewer unhinged outbursts during long conversations—"it still often gets things wrong."</p>
<p>Nadella told Wired that Microsoft has found "very practical stuff that reduces hallucination" and that seemingly serves as a stopgap until the technology improves and new solutions emerge.</p>
<p>Nadella also said that sometimes "hallucinations" are desirable, though, and any solutions to limit "hallucinations" should be mindful that users should maintain the option to use AI chatbots for creative purposes, too.</p>
<p>OpenAI did not immediately respond to Ars' request to comment. A Microsoft spokesperson told Ars that another reason why the company launched the new Bing preview was to respond to half of all standard web searches that typically go unanswered. Microsoft is also continually seeking to improve the authority and credibility of the web results that underpin their chat mode response, the spokesperson said, and stands prepared to quickly fix unanticipated issues that arise.</p>
<p>"Our approach is to make AI tools available to people responsibly with guardrails in place so we can get feedback, continue to learn, and quickly improve these tools, as we have done with Bing," Microsoft's spokesperson told Ars.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>The rivalry goes beyond chatbots</h2>
<p>When Wired asked Nadella why Microsoft invested in OpenAI when it has been investing in its own large language model for decades, Nadella said that he could see that "OpenAI was going after the same thing as" Microsoft. Rather than "trying to train five different foundational models" at the same time, Nadella saw an opportunity to partner with OpenAI to make "one foundation" where the two independent companies could "go after one goal, with discipline."</p>
<p>"We said, 'Let's go after this and build one thing that really captures the imagination of the world,'” Nadella told Wired.</p>
<p>But WSJ reported that the partnership is much more complicated than that.</p>
<p>Further tension and confusion has brewed within Microsoft's in-house AI team, which has "complained about diminished spending." Most employees are set back by a lack of "access to the inner workings" of OpenAI's technology, which is particularly painful for employees attempting to integrate that tech into various Microsoft products. There's also the awkward reality that OpenAI's and Microsoft's sales teams "sometimes pitch the same customers." Much of this "drama" amounts to typical infighting that happens any time two companies pair up, WSJ reported, but there's no ignoring the conflict inherent to both sides attempting to maintain independence while reaping maximum profits by selling access to the same technology.</p>
<p>Despite these tensions, Nadella told Wired that OpenAI "bet on" Microsoft, and Microsoft "bet on" OpenAI. He still envisions "a good commercial partnership" between the independent companies and considered Microsoft's investment in OpenAI as "a long-term stable deal."</p>
<p>Increasingly, it looks like one way to assuage tension is to bring the companies even closer together in partnership. WSJ noted that Nadella announced last month that the Bing search engine would soon be integrated into ChatGPT, which he said was "just the start of what we plan to do with our partners in OpenAI to bring the best of Bing to the ChatGPT experience."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947867&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/report-microsoft-launched-bing-chatbot-despite-openai-warning-it-wasnt-ready/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft is selling screens, batteries, SSDs, and more for DIY Surface repairs</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947841</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/microsoft-adds-pricey-diy-surface-repair-parts-to-online-store/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[right to repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surface laptop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surface pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surface pro 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surface pro 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surface pro x]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has offered repair manuals for a while; now it has parts to match.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/DSC00576-1-800x533.jpeg" alt="The Surface Pro 8's replaceable SSD."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/DSC00576-1.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1707" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The Surface Pro 8's replaceable SSD. (credit: Andrew Cunningham)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Microsoft offers <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/100440">first-party service manuals</a> for several generations' worth of Surface hardware, in keeping with a commitment to improve its repairability and sustainability efforts. Today, Microsoft is <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/devices/2023/06/14/announcing-the-availability-of-consumer-replacement-components-for-surface-devices/">taking the next step</a>, listing <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/b/surface-repair-parts">dozens of replacement parts</a> for Surface tablets, laptops, and all-in-ones on the Microsoft Store.</p>

<p>The screens, kickstands, batteries, keyboards, camera modules, and other odds and ends are available for the Surface Pro 8, 9, and X; Surface Laptops 2 through 5 plus the Go 2 and the Studio; and the Studio and Studio 2+ all-in-one desktops. Most of the major components are pretty expensive—the display for a Surface Studio 2+ is $1,750 all by itself—but they're cheaper than buying a new device, you won't have to pay for labor costs, and you can be sure you're getting genuine first-party components.</p>
<p>"When purchasing a replacement component, you will receive the part and relevant collateral components (such as screws if applicable)," wrote Microsoft VP Tim McGuiggan. "Tools needed for the repair are sold separately through iFixit. It is essential to follow the instructions in the applicable Microsoft Service Guide or article."</p>
<p>Microsoft is also selling some first-party Surface SSD upgrades for anyone who bought a 128GB or 256GB drive and regretted it later. But the way they're listed is a bit odd—there are three separate listings for the <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/d/replacement-ssd-for-surface-pro-8/8zr1w52nbmgj">Surface Pro 8</a>, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/d/replacement-ssd-for-surface-pro-9/8xpxwj7pqc0x">Surface Pro 9</a>, and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/d/replacement-ssd-for-surface-pro-x/8rq55htc5x41">Surface Pro X</a>, plus more for various generations of Surface Laptop and Surface Laptop Go. And though all of the drives are physically identical, the ones for the more recent Surface devices are a bit more expensive than the others in some capacities.</p>
<p>The drives may differ in subtle ways that the listings don't mention—differing PCI Express configurations, maybe, or just making sure that drives are replaced with identical models for support purposes. It's worth noting that there are mixed reviews for <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/01/its-getting-easier-to-buy-bigger-ssds-for-the-steam-deck-and-surface-pcs/">third-party M.2 2230 drives</a> like the <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BQG6FM45/?tag=arstech20-20">Sabrent Rocket</a> in Surface devices; many users report that they work just fine, and others report instability, overheating, and sleep issues. Though Microsoft's drives cost more per gigabyte than Sabrent's, and none of them go up to 2TB, it's nice to have a first-party option available to minimize these kinds of issues.</p>
<p>The first few generations of Surface devices were infamously difficult to repair, with proprietary parts and glued-together frames that earned the company <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2013/02/ifixit-teardown-shows-surface-pro-is-a-tough-nut-to-crack/">some very low scores on iFixit's repairability scale</a>. More recent versions have been better, partly because of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/10/microsoft-is-evaluating-right-to-repair-options-for-xbox-and-surface-devices/">pressure from Microsoft shareholders</a> to improve repairability and sustainability, and partly because a handful of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/03/tech-makers-must-provide-repairs-for-up-to-10-years-under-proposed-eu-law/">countries</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2022/12/weakened-right-to-repair-bill-is-signed-into-law-by-new-yorks-governor/">US states</a> are beginning to propose and pass right-to-repair laws that would mandate some of these changes anyway.</p>
<p>Parts will initially be available in the US, Canada, and France, with "updates on additional markets" coming "in the future."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947841&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/microsoft-adds-pricey-diy-surface-repair-parts-to-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IBM compensates for errors, gets usable results out of quantum processor</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947845</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/ibm-compensates-for-errors-gets-usable-results-out-of-quantum-processor/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Timmer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ibm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ising model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qubits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[May be a way to squeeze useful work out before we get quantum error correction.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-2-800x450.jpeg" alt="Image of a processor chip split into layers and expanded."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-2.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="608" data-width="1080">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> IBM's Eagle processor has reached Rev3, which means lower noise qubits. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://research.ibm.com/blog/eagle-quantum-processor-performance">IBM</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Today's quantum processors are error-prone. While the probabilities are small—less than 1 percent in many cases—each operation we perform on each qubit, including basic things like reading its state, has a significant error rate. If we try an operation that needs a lot of qubits, or a lot of operations on a smaller number of qubits, then errors become inevitable.</p>
<p>Long term, the plan is to solve that using <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/02/google-shows-current-generation-qubits-good-enough-for-error-correction/">error-corrected qubits</a>. But these will require multiple high-quality qubits for every bit of information, meaning we'll need thousands of qubits that are better than anything we can currently make. Given that we probably won't reach that point until the next decade at the earliest, it raises the question of whether quantum computers can do anything interesting in the meantime.</p>
<p>In a publication in today's Nature, IBM researchers make a strong case for the answer to that being yes. Using a technique termed "error mitigation," they managed to overcome the problems with today's qubits and produce an accurate result despite the noise in the system. And they did so in a way that clearly outperformed similar calculations on classical computers.</p>
<h2>Living with noise</h2>
<p>If we think of quantum error correction as a way to avoid the noise that keeps qubits from accurately performing operations, error mitigation can be viewed as accepting that the noise is inevitable. It's a means of measuring the typical errors, compensating for them after the fact and producing an estimate of the real result that's hidden within the noise.</p>
<p>An early method of performing error mitigation (termed probabilistic error cancellation) involved sampling the behavior of the quantum processor to develop a model of the typical noise and then subtracting the noise from the measured output of an actual calculation. But as the number of qubits involved in the calculation goes up, this method gets a bit impractical to use—you have to do too much sampling.</p>
<p>So instead, the researchers turned to a method where they intentionally amplified and then measured the processor's noise at different levels. These measurements are used to estimate a function that produces similar output as the actual measurements. That function can then have its noise set to zero to produce an estimate of what the processor would do without any noise at all.</p>
<p>To test this system, the researchers turned to what's called an Ising model, which is easiest to think of as a grid of electrons where each electron's spin influences that of its neighbors. As you step forward in time, each step sees the spins change in response to the influence of their neighbors, which alters the overall state of the grid. The new configuration of spins will then influence each other, and the process will repeat as time progresses.</p>
<p>While an Ising model involves simplified, idealized behavior, it has features that show up in a variety of physical systems, so they've been studied pretty widely. (D-Wave, which makes quantum annealers, recently published a paper in which its hardware <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/04/quantum-effects-of-d-waves-hardware-boosts-its-performance/">identified the ground state</a> of these systems, so they may sound familiar.) And as the number of objects in the model increases, their behavior quickly becomes complex enough that classical computers struggle to calculate their state.</p>
<p>It's possible to perform the calculations on a quantum computer by performing operations on pairs of qubits. To simplify matters, IBM used an Ising model where the grid was configured in a way that coincides with the physical arrangement of qubits on its processor. But this wasn't a case where the processor was simply being used to model its own behavior; as mentioned above, Ising models existed independently of quantum hardware.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Quantum vs. classical</h2>
<p>To start with, the researchers limited the number of spins they were modeling to ensure that its behavior could be calculated on a traditional computer. This work showed that the error mitigation procedure worked; once the noise was compensated for, the numbers from the quantum calculation matched those from the classical computation, even out to over a dozen time steps. But it was relatively simple to scale up the model to where the classical computer (a 64-core processor with 128GB of memory) started to struggle.</p>
<p>This happened at the point where the system required 68 qubits to model. From there, the researchers used software that estimated the system's behavior on the classical computer, which allowed it to keep up for longer at the cost of some accuracy. Even so, it was possible to scale up the model's size to where 127 qubits were needed, which is well past the point where classical calculations can keep up.</p>
<p>"The mitigation technique was basically able to run for a larger size than I could do an exact simulation on a classical computer using an exact classical method simulation," IBM's <a href="https://researcher.watson.ibm.com/researcher/view.php?person=us-jay.gambetta">Jay Gambetta</a> told Ars. "So it's outside the reach of exact classical methods. But then in classical methods, you also have approximate methods that can scale more efficiently. [The quantum calculation] was also more accurate than those approximate classical methods."</p>
<p>The researchers estimate that tracing the system's behavior through 20 time steps would require over 400 petabytes of memory.</p>
<p>So, this appears to be a clear case of quantum computers outperforming classical computers on a potentially interesting problem. And Gambetta suggested that showing noise mitigation works on a simple system like the Ising model is essential if we're going to start applying the approach to more complicated problems that could have practical applications. But pushing things further isn't going to simply be a matter of adding more qubits.</p>
<h2>The complications</h2>
<p>IBM has <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2022/11/ibm-pushes-qubit-count-over-400-with-new-processor/">a quantum processor with over 400 qubits</a>, so why limit things to the 127 qubits used here? There are a couple of reasons for this. IBM chose its smaller, 127-qubit Eagle processor for the work because that has already reached Revision 3, while its larger Osprey processor is still in its first iteration. The two revisions have been used to improve the performance of the qubits, cutting down on the noise that needs to be compensated for.</p>
<p>And that brings us to the second reason: compensating for noise is computationally expensive and needs to be done using classical computers. Doing the sampling of the noise on the quantum computer only took about five minutes. But even for a smaller problem, the full noise mitigation process required four hours; that's compared to eight hours to simply model the system on a classical computer. Still, the scaling was better; a somewhat larger problem required about 30 hours to model, while the noise mitigation took 9.5 hours.</p>
<p>One consequence of this means that adding enough qubits can also potentially make error mitigation computationally intractable. "Error mitigation still scales exponentially," Gambetta said, "but it's a weaker exponential than the simulation cost."</p>
<p>But IBM thinks that there are two reasons for optimism here. For starters, the research team says the algorithms involved in the error mitigation are "dominated by classical processing delays that stand to be largely eliminated through conceptually straightforward optimizations." So there's likely to be a speedup there. The second is that the time involved scales as a function of the error rates in the quantum hardware—lower those, and it will speed up the classical portion of the calculation.</p>
<p>Gambetta is especially excited about a processor called Heron, which is on IBM's road map for this year. Regarding speed-of-gate operations, Gambetta said, "Our preliminary results suggest that [Heron will] be somewhere like five times better than Eagle." Since the possibility that the system suffers decoherence (the loss of its quantum state) is a function of time, less time on operations means that the calculation is more likely to be completed before decoherence becomes an issue. And fewer errors also means a faster error mitigation process.</p>
<p>All of this makes people at IBM optimistic that error mitigation is a route toward performing useful calculations on quantum hardware long before we reach the point where error-corrected qubits are possible. As the paper concludes, "A noisy quantum processor, even before the advent of fault-tolerant quantum computing, produces reliable expectation values at a scale beyond 100 qubits and non-trivial circuit depth leads to the conclusion that there is indeed merit to pursuing research towards deriving a practical computational advantage from noise-limited quantum circuits."</p>
<p>Nature, 2023. DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41586-023-06096-3">10.1038/s41586-023-06096-3</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947845&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/ibm-compensates-for-errors-gets-usable-results-out-of-quantum-processor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vulcan aces engine test, but upper stage anomaly will delay launch for a while</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947706</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2023/06/vulcan-rocket-completes-critical-test-but-launch-slipping-toward-end-of-2023/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 16:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ula]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulcan rocket]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Working corrective action and retest."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/vulcan-1-800x533.jpg" alt="United Launch Alliance's Vulcan rocket completes a &quot;flight readiness firing&quot; last week. "/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/vulcan-1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1333" data-width="2000">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> United Launch Alliance's Vulcan rocket completes a &quot;flight readiness firing&quot; last week.  (credit: United Launch Alliance)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>The Vulcan rocket took a critical step toward its much-anticipated debut launch last week with a successful engine-firing test. However, one critical issue remains unresolved before the large booster can lift off.</p>
<p>This final hurdle involves modifications to the rocket's Centaur V upper stage, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/04/ula-continues-investigation-of-centaur-stage-anomaly/">which exploded</a> during a test at the end of March. On Tuesday, the chief executive of Vulcan manufacturer United Launch Alliance, Tory Bruno, <a href="https://twitter.com/torybruno/status/1668314430785097728">wrote on Twitter</a> that a root cause of the failure had been identified, and the investigation has been concluded.</p>
<p>As part of their recent updates, neither Bruno nor United Launch Alliance established a new target launch date. Two sources indicated to Ars, however, that this flight likely would not occur before the fourth quarter of this year due to additional needed work.</p>
<h2>Flight readiness firing</h2>
<p>United Launch Alliance completed an essential milestone on June 7 when it conducted a hot-fire test of Vulcan's first-stage engines. The BE-4 engines, built by Blue Origin, began the ignition sequence at T-4.88 seconds and, according to the company, throttled up to the target power level for two seconds before powering down.</p>
<p>Although the company needs to fully review data from the test, it appeared to be a complete success. This long-awaited firing of the main engines closes what had been believed to be the biggest outstanding issue with the rocket prior to its debut launch—before the Centaur anomaly occurred. Delivery of the BE-4 engines had been delayed for several years while Blue Origin completed its development and testing.</p>
<p>"The team is reviewing the data from the systems involved in today’s test and, in parallel, continue with the Centaur V test stand anomaly investigation," the company said in a statement after the test firing. "Pending the data review and the investigation results, we will develop a launch plan. Testing is an integral part of our launch vehicle development program, and we will fly when we believe it is safe to launch."</p>
<h2>Centaur update</h2>
<p>In replies on Twitter Tuesday, Bruno provided the first public confirmation that the United Launch Alliance's investigation into the Centaur failure is complete. Although the report is not public, it appears that the hydrogen tank failed during a pressure test at Marshall Space Flight Center in Alabama.</p>

<p>"The super thin, high performance steel skin needs to be a little thicker near the top of the dome," <a href="https://twitter.com/torybruno/status/1668571711061610496">Bruno said</a>, adding, "Working corrective action and retest."</p>
<p>This comment implies that a Centaur qualification tank will be made more robust and then undergo pressure testing at Marshall later this summer. It is unclear whether the flight version of the Centaur stage, which had already been delivered to the launch site in Cape Canaveral, Florida, will also need to be modified. If so, this testing and modification work will likely take a few months.</p>
<p>Asked whether the flight tank needed to be modified, Bruno replied cryptically, <a href="https://twitter.com/torybruno/status/1668571711061610496">saying</a>, "Working on all of that now."</p>
<h2>Space Force is keeping tabs</h2>
<p>Throughout all of this, United Launch Alliance has been working closely with the US Space Force, which has been the company's most important customer since ULA's inception nearly two decades ago.</p>
<p>In 2020, as part of its "National Security Space Launch Phase 2" program, <a href="https://www.af.mil/News/Article-Display/Article/2305576/space-force-awards-national-security-space-launch-phase-2-launch-service-contra/">the US military awarded</a> United Launch Alliance and SpaceX five-year contracts to launch about 40 missions between fiscal year 2022 and 2028. As part of this program, United Launch Alliance won 60 percent of the launches, and SpaceX got 40 percent.</p>
<p>However, there have been growing concerns about the readiness of Vulcan, which was supposed to start launching national security missions in 2022. That will now not happen until at least 2024 because Vulcan must fly two "certification" flights before it is deemed safe enough for valuable reconnaissance satellites.</p>
<p>Notably, in <a href="https://www.ssc.spaceforce.mil/Portals/3/Documents/PRESS%20RELEASES/Space%20Systems%20Command%20assigns%20missions%20for%20National%20Security%20Space%20Launch%20Phase%202%20FY23%20Order%20Year.pdf?ver=FN1MZufLWN99U7m3cM0XPQ%3D%3D">an announcement last Friday</a>, Space Systems Command said it recently assigned a dozen Phase 2 missions to the two launch companies. These launches were split equally between United Launch Alliance and SpaceX rather than in a 60-40 split.</p>
<p>Additionally, just last week, a US Government Accountability Office <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-23-106059.pdf">report</a> mentioned that delays were causing military officials working on the Phase 2 launch program to consider their options. "In the event that Vulcan is unavailable for future missions, program officials stated that the Phase 2 contract allows for the ability to reassign missions to the other provider," the report states.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947706&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/space/2023/06/vulcan-rocket-completes-critical-test-but-launch-slipping-toward-end-of-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>52</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google risks forced breakup of ad business as EU alleges shocking misconduct</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947761</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/google-may-soon-be-ordered-to-break-up-its-lucrative-ad-business-eu-warns/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 16:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google could lose huge parts of its $225 billion ad business.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-1258510752-800x534.jpg" alt="Google risks forced breakup of ad business as EU alleges shocking misconduct"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-1258510752.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/logo-of-the-online-search-engine-google-on-june-07-2023-in-news-photo/1258510752">Thomas Trutschel / Contributor | Photothek</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Google may soon be ordered to break up its lucrative ad business, which amounted to <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266249/advertising-revenue-of-google/">nearly $225 billion</a> in 2022 and represented nearly 80 percent of Google's total revenue. Today, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/googles-ad-tech-dominance-spurs-more-antitrust-charges-report-says/">as expected</a>, the European Commission (EC) sent Google a statement of objections, detailing ad tech antitrust charges and explaining exactly why the EC thinks that breaking up Google's ad business may be the only acceptable remedy.</p>
<p>"We are concerned that Google may have illegally distorted competition in the online advertising technology industry," Margrethe Vestager, the EC's executive vice president, said in <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/speech_23_3288">remarks</a> published today.</p>
<p>According to Vestager, an EC investigation launched in 2021 found that Google may have favored its own ad tech services when serving as an intermediary ad exchange, matching advertiser supply and publisher demand for advertising space online.</p>
<p>To the EC, it seems like Google has its hand in too many pots to be trusted to conduct business fairly. Google operates an ad exchange, AdX, as well as ad tech services for advertisers—Google Ads and Google Display &amp; Video 360 (DV 360)—and services for publishers, DoubleClick For Publishers (DFP).</p>
<p>Vestager said there's potential for misconduct because "Google may hold a dominant position on both ends of the ad tech supply chain" and "appears to have abused its market position" by ensuring that both advertising and publisher services allegedly favored AdX over other ad exchanges when matching advertisers and publishers.</p>
<p>By allegedly favoring AdX, Vestager said that Google was able to charge "a high fee for its 'exchange' services."</p>
<p>Two examples she provided show Google's seeming self-preferencing conduct that has led the EC to expect that Google breaking up its ad business may be the only path forward for the ad tech industry to remain fair.</p>
<p>First, when DFP selects ads for publishers, it is supposed to find ads that "bring the most value to them" by auctioning off the online placement to advertisers who place bids in a "sealed bid auction." This means that each advertiser supposedly had no prior knowledge of how other advertisers were bidding. However, the EC found that Google was allegedly "allowing Google's own participant in that auction, AdX, to open the sealed envelopes of all other rivals before placing its own bid." This allegedly gave AdX an unfair advantage to beat out competitors for DFP placements.</p>
<p>The second scenario the EC pointed to as being potentially problematic focuses on Google Ads practices. When advertisers buy Google Ads, the expectation, the EC suggested, is that Google would place bids on as many ad exchanges as possible to get the highest distribution for ads. That wasn't what Google was doing, the EC alleged. Instead, Google was allegedly only—or "almost only"—placing bids on its own exchange, AdX. This practice, the EC alleged, "make[s] AdX the most attractive marketplace" and "gave it a significant competitive advantage over rival ad exchanges."</p>
<p>These are only two examples of Google's alleged self-preferencing in its ad tech business. Vestager said there are "a number of similar" other examples that concerned the EC.</p>
<p>"We see the risk that Google's conduct distorted competition among ad exchanges: rather than letting the best of the ad exchanges win the race, the helping hand of the powerful Google ecosystem gave Google's own exchange a unique head start over all other rivals in the industry," Vestager said.</p>
<p>Because of this, "AdX could afford to keep its commissions high without losing its advertisers," Vestager said.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Solution: Break up Google’s ad business</h2>
<p>While investigating Google's ad business, the EC consulted with competition authorities within the European Union—in France, Denmark, Italy, and Portugal—as well as those beyond, in the United Kingdom and the United States. In particular, the EC's cooperation with the US Department of Justice "has been close and fruitful," Vestager said, and the parties share "the same view as to what is good for competition, and ultimately, how to best remedy the issues for the benefit of consumers and citizens."</p>
<p>This level of cooperation could indicate that ad tech antitrust probes outside of the EU could draw the same conclusions as the EC once the EC concludes its probe. And that could be a big problem for Google, which is financially motivated to thwart a potential break-up order to keep its ad tech business operating as usual.</p>
<p>If the EC is able to prove that Google's ad tech business operated illegally, Vestager said that Google couldn't be trusted to change its behaviors.</p>
<p>"This market is a highly technical market," Vestager said. "It is very dynamic. The detection of these behaviors can therefore be very challenging. We have seen this play out concretely: each time a practice was detected by the industry, Google subtly modified its behavior so as to make it more difficult to detect but with the same objectives, with the same effects."</p>
<p>Instead of trusting Google to change its behavior and risking Google continuing self-preferencing misconduct, "just under a different disguise," Vestager said that Google would need to break up its business to mollify anti-competitive concerns.</p>
<p>That could mean that Google could be forced to "divest part of its services," Vestager said. If Google sold its sell-side services—including both publisher services through DFP and its ad exchange AdX— that would likely "put an end to the conflicts of interest" allegedly uncovered by the EC's investigation.</p>
<p>Google received the EC's full statement of objections today and now has a chance to respond to allegations. The EC's media contact Sara Simonini told Ars that "there is no legal deadline for bringing an antitrust investigation to an end."</p>
<p>"The duration of an antitrust investigation depends on a number of factors, including the complexity of the case, the extent to which the companies concerned cooperate with the Commission, and the exercise of their rights of defense," Simonini told Ars.</p>
<p>Google now has the option of exercising its rights of defense and will have access to the EC's file detailing the alleged misconduct. Once Google receives that file, the company will have 11 weeks to respond in writing to the EC's statement of objections, or it can ask for a deadline extension or an oral hearing "conducted by an independent Hearing Officer," Simonini told Ars.</p>
<p>Google did not immediately respond to Ars' request for comment. [<strong>Update, 4:28 pm ET:</strong> Google's ad tech revenue was roughly a fifth of the size of its search revenue in the <a href="https://abc.xyz/investor/static/pdf/2023Q1_alphabet_earnings_release.pdf?cache=0924ccf">first quarter of 2023. </a>Search revenue comprises the bulk of Google's ad revenue and is not a focus of the EC's probe. Google's VP of Global Ads, Dan Taylor, provided a statement to Ars, confirming that Google disagreed "with the EC's view" on its ad tech business and plans to "respond accordingly."</p>
<p>“Our advertising technology tools help websites and apps fund their content, and enable businesses of all sizes to effectively reach new customers," Taylor said. "Google remains committed to creating value for our publisher and advertiser partners in this highly competitive sector. The Commission’s investigation focuses on a narrow aspect of our advertising business and is not new."]</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947761&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/google-may-soon-be-ordered-to-break-up-its-lucrative-ad-business-eu-warns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Comcast complains to FCC that listing all of its monthly fees is too hard</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947752</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/comcast-complains-to-fcc-that-listing-all-of-its-monthly-fees-is-too-hard/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband labels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Comcast blasted for seeking "loopholes" in rule requiring disclosure of all fees.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/getty-comcast-van-800x533.jpg" alt="A Comcast service van seen from behind."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/getty-comcast-van.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1333" data-width="2000">Enlarge</a> (credit: Getty Images | Smith Collection/Gado )</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Comcast is not happy about new federal rules that will require it to provide broadband customers with labels displaying exact <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2022/01/fcc-aims-to-stop-broadband-bill-shock-reviving-plan-nixed-by-ajit-pai/">prices and other information</a> about Internet service plans.<div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/fcc-broadband-label.jpg"><img alt='Broadband label that ISPs will be required to display to consumers at the point of sale.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/fcc-broadband-label-300x699.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/fcc-broadband-label-640x1492.jpg 2x" alt='Broadband label that ISPs will be required to display to consumers at the point of sale.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/fcc-broadband-label.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Broadband label that ISPs will be required to display to consumers at the point of sale.</a> (credit: FCC)</p></div></p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/ecfs/document/10608230225212/1">filing</a> last week, Comcast told the Federal Communications Commission that it is "working diligently to put in place the systems and processes necessary to create, maintain, and display the labels as required." But according to Comcast, "two aspects of the Commission's Order impose significant administrative burdens and unnecessary complexity in complying with the broadband label requirements."</p>
<p>Comcast noted that five major cable and telecom industry trade groups <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/ecfs/document/10117331109471/1">petitioned the FCC</a> in January to change the rules. Comcast's new filing urged the FCC to grant the petition "as soon as possible before the rules become effective to help providers streamline and simplify their labeling processes, which will ultimately benefit consumers."</p>
<p>The FCC was required to implement broadband label rules in a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/11/congress-oks-42-billion-to-deploy-100mbps-broadband-in-unserved-areas/">2021 law</a> passed by Congress. Although the FCC <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-requires-broadband-providers-display-labels-help-consumers">approved</a> the label rules in November 2022, it's not clear when they will take effect. They are subject to a federal Office of Management and Budget (OMB) review because of requirements in the US Paperwork Reduction Act. Medium-sized and large ISPs would be required to comply six months after the OMB review, while providers with 100,000 or fewer subscribers would have one year to comply.</p>
<p>"The label hasn't even reached consumers yet, but Comcast is already trying to create loopholes. This request would allow the big ISPs to continue hiding the true cost of service and frustrating customers with poor service. Congress created the label to end these practices, not maintain them, and Comcast offers no compelling reason for the FCC to violate Congress' intent," Joshua Stager, policy director at media advocacy group Free Press, told Ars. Stager previously <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/03/obama-era-fccs-broadband-nutrition-labels-could-make-a-comeback/">advocated</a> for the broadband labels when he was deputy director of New America's Open Technology Institute.</p>
<p>The FCC rules require ISPs to display the labels at the point of sale. The labels must disclose broadband prices, introductory rates, data allowances, Internet speeds, and include links to information about an ISP's network management practices and privacy policies.<!--adbreak--></p>
<h2>Comcast doesn’t want to list all monthly fees</h2>
<p>Comcast pointed to "recent filings regarding the Commission's underestimation of the burdens associated with implementing the broadband consumer label rules." Those filings came from Verizon, AT&amp;T, Lumen (aka CenturyLink), and a trade group representing rural broadband providers.</p>
<p>Comcast and other ISPs have annoyed customers for many years by advertising low prices and then charging much bigger monthly bills by tacking on a variety of fees. While some of these fees are related to government-issued requirements and others are not, poorly trained customer service reps have been known to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/01/the-lies-comcast-allegedly-told-customers-to-hide-full-cost-of-service/">falsely tell customers</a> that fees created by Comcast are mandated by the government.</p>
<p>The FCC rules will force ISPs to accurately describe fees in labels given to customers, but Comcast said it wants the FCC to rescind a requirement related to "fees that ISPs may, but are not obligated to, pass through to customers." These include state Universal Service fees and other local fees.</p>
<p>As Comcast makes clear, it isn't required to pass these costs on to customers in the form of separate fees. Comcast could stop charging the fees and raise its advertised prices by the corresponding amount to more accurately convey its actual prices to customers. Instead, Comcast wants the FCC to change the rule so that it can continue charging the fees without itemizing them.</p>
<p>The portion of the FCC order that Comcast and other ISPs object to says that "providers must list all recurring monthly fees," including "all charges that providers impose at their discretion, <em>i.e.</em>, charges not mandated by a government."</p>
<p>Comcast wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>[T]he Order appropriately refrains from requiring ISPs to itemize state and local taxes, recognizing that they "often vary according to a customer's geographic location." The Order adopts the same treatment for government fees that a "relevant state or local government 'mandate[s]'" must be passed through to customers... However, the Order appears to take a different tack with respect to fees that ISPs may, but are not obligated to, pass through to customers. The language of the Order creates much uncertainty over how ISPs must treat these fees on their labels because it may be read to require ISPs to itemize each of these pass-through government-imposed fees on their labels... If these fees must be itemized, a separate label must be created for each unique combination of applicable nonmandatory pass-through government fees. Itemizing these fees would substantially increase the burden on providers to generate and maintain their labels, particularly as the fees are subject to change, in some cases as often as quarterly.</p></blockquote>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>FCC urged to reject loopholes</h2>
<p>Comcast said the FCC should let providers "list state and local government fees on labels the same way they list state and local taxes" or at least "permit the listing of the maximum amount of fees that may apply."</p>
<p>Even if Comcast's wish is granted, the cable company said it would still have to "create 251 separate broadband consumer labels to comply with the rules." Comcast's filing also specifies the number of labels it would have to create if the FCC declines to change the rules, but that number is redacted in the publicly available version of Comcast's submission.</p>
<p>Harold Feld, senior VP of consumer advocacy group Public Knowledge, said the FCC rules should remain unchanged.</p>
<p>"These rules are important for informing consumers about the basis for the cost of broadband and to ensure that ISPs comply with the rules," Feld told Ars. "In other words, they do exactly what the statute instructed. The reasons given to change these rules were not compelling when the trade associations filed their petition for reconsideration, and they have not become more compelling now."</p>
<p>The FCC, Feld said, "should reject the request to create loopholes which would obscure what fees providers decide to pass on versus those that are mandated by state law. It is an effort to pass blame to the state which properly belongs to the ISP."</p>
<h2>Documenting compliance</h2>
<p>Secondly, Comcast objects to a record-keeping requirement that seems designed to ensure that ISPs are following the rules. The record-keeping rule relates to providing labels through "alternate sales channels" such as retail stores or customer service phone calls. The FCC said that ISPs can meet the label requirement in these sales channels either by providing a hard copy of the label or by "directing the consumer to the specific web page on which the label appears by, for example, providing Internet access in the retail location or giving the customer a card with the printed URL or a QR code, or orally providing information from the label to the consumer over the phone."</p>
<p>ISPs that don't provide hard copies in those sales channels must document each instance in which they direct a consumer to a label. Essentially, ISPs must be able to prove that they pointed each consumer to the label.<!--adbreak--></p>
<p>Providers that don't provide hard copies of the label in the alternate sales channels "shall document each instance when it directs a consumer to a label at an alternate sales channel and retain such documentation for two years," the FCC rule says.</p>
<p>Comcast told the FCC that ISPs shouldn't have to collect these records. Comcast said that due to the "number of customer interactions in Comcast retail stores and over the phone," maintaining these "otherwise-unnecessary records imposes substantial additional burdens." Comcast urged the FCC to "act quickly to clarify that ISPs may comply with the Order's requirement by simply documenting their practices and procedures for displaying the label at alternate sales channels."</p>
<h2>Advocates wanted stricter rules</h2>
<p>Comcast also objected to how the record-keeping requirement was implemented. "The Order does not explain or justify this requirement, which is not reflected anywhere in the actual rules and was not even addressed in the underlying proceeding," Comcast said. The Comcast statement about the "actual rules" differentiates between the <a href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-47/chapter-I/subchapter-A/part-8">rules themselves</a> and the much longer order in which the FCC explained its reasoning and how the rules will be enforced.</p>
<p>Before the FCC approved its rules last year, cable-industry lobby group NCTA-The Internet &amp; Television Association <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/ecfs/document/103242459303274/1">urged</a> the commission to reject proposals to require that broadband labels be sent to consumers with every monthly bill. Stager believes that provision would have made it into the final rules if the FCC wasn't still operating with a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/05/biden-chooses-new-fcc-commissioner-hopes-senate-wont-reject-this-one-too/">2-2 partisan deadlock</a> due to the Senate <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/03/bidens-fcc-pick-withdraws-regrets-that-isps-get-to-choose-their-regulators/">refusing to confirm</a> Biden nominee Gigi Sohn.</p>
<p>"Comcast already succeeded in watering down the label last year when they defeated a requirement to display the label where customers would actually see it—on their monthly bill," Stager said. "Despite strong support for this common-sense rule, the FCC didn't have the votes. It's a loophole that many ISPs, which are notoriously adept at hiding billing disclosures, will try to drive a truck through."</p>
<p>FCC Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel recently <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/03/fcc-chair-proposes-ban-on-deceptive-broadcast-tv-and-regional-sports-fees/">proposed</a> similar pricing transparency rules for the TV services offered by cable and satellite companies. TV providers like Comcast generally advertise rates that don't include charges such as the "Broadcast TV" and "Regional Sports Network" fees. Rosenworcel's proposal would require cable and direct-broadcast satellite providers to "state the total cost of video programming service clearly and prominently, including broadcast retransmission consent, regional sports programming, and other programming-related fees, as a prominent single line item on subscribers' bills and in promotional materials."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947752&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/comcast-complains-to-fcc-that-listing-all-of-its-monthly-fees-is-too-hard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>191</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Federal judge temporarily blocks Microsoft/Activision deal</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947743</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/federal-judge-temporarily-blocks-microsoft-activision-deal/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 14:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Restraining order "maintain[s] the status quo" as FTC's case moves forward.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/xbabk.png" alt="Getting all these games to be officially under the Microsoft banner (rather than just visually, as seen here) will take a while longer, at the very least."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/xbabk.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="450" data-width="800">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Getting all these games to be officially under the Microsoft banner (rather than just visually, as seen here) will take a while longer, at the very least. (credit: Microsoft)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>A federal judge has issued a temporary restraining order blocking Microsoft's long-planned acquisition of Activision, pending hearings on <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/report-ftc-will-file-to-block-microsofts-69b-activision-blizzard-acquisition/">the preliminary injunction being sought by the Federal Trade Commission in the case</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/ftc-v-microsoft-order-re-tro-and-preliminary-injunction.pdf">The temporary order</a> issued by District Court Judge Jacqueline Corley doesn't do much to suggest which way the court is leaning on the merits of the FTC's case. A Microsoft spokesperson even <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2023/06/13/microsoft-activision-blizzard-deal-blocked/e7f4f7a2-0a57-11ee-8132-a84600f3bb9b_story.html">acknowledged to the Associated Press</a> that "a temporary restraining order makes sense until we can receive a decision from the Court, which is moving swiftly."</p>
<p>The order "maintain[s] the status quo," as Judge Corley puts it, by preventing Microsoft and Activision from closing their deal while a more permanent decision on the injunction is pending. And while Microsoft and Activision have said in the past that they will wait for the regulatory process to finish before completing their proposed deal, the FTC <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/federal-court-grants-ftcs-request-to-temporarily-block-microsoft-activision-tie-up-120056268.html">told Yahoo Finance</a> that they sought the restraining order based on "public reporting that Microsoft and Activision Blizzard are considering closing their deal imminently."</p>
<p>The first hearing on the FTC's preliminary injunction request is scheduled to start on June 22, giving Microsoft until Friday to file its initial response in the matter. That tight schedule might be to Microsoft's overall benefit, as Activision CEO Bobby Kotick <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/report-ftc-will-file-to-block-microsofts-69b-activision-blizzard-acquisition/">said Monday</a> that the FTC's federal injunction request "accelerates the legal process" and that their "excellent legal team has been preparing for this move for more than a year."</p>
<p>If and when that injunction is granted, the deal will continue to be on pause as the FTC's wider antitrust case moves forward.</p>
<p>Despite the speedy schedule, the current court timeline makes it extremely unlikely that Microsoft and Activision will be able to close their deal before <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/01/ftc-delays-could-send-microsoft-and-activision-back-to-the-bargaining-table/">a contractual July 18 deadline</a> set when the acquisition was first proposed early last year. While Microsoft would technically have to pay a significant "breakup fee" if that deadline isn't met, both sides will likely renegotiate a later deadline pending the outcome of outstanding legal issues.</p>
<p>The FTC previously filed a separate "administrative complaint" against the Microsoft Activision deal <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/12/ftc-files-suit-to-stop-microsofts-69-billion-activision-purchase/">back in December</a>. That case, which will be argued in front of an FTC administrative law judge, isn't set to begin until August 2.</p>
<p>Outside the US, Microsoft and Activision are also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/05/activision-appeals-uks-irrational-unlawful-blocking-of-microsoft-merger/">appealing</a> a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/04/uk-government-blocks-microsofts-proposed-activision-purchase/">UK government decision to block the merger</a> based on competition concerns in the cloud gaming market. A hearing on that appeal is set for July 28.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947743&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/federal-judge-temporarily-blocks-microsoft-activision-deal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Satellites keep photobombing space images. Astronomers need a fix</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947734</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/satellites-keep-photobombing-spaces-images-astronomers-need-a-fix/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WIRED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hubble Space Telescope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-earth orbit satellites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new technique could aid Hubble Space Telescope users.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/satellite-streak-800x533.jpg" alt="image of a galaxy showing a streak from a satellite"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/satellite-streak.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1493" data-width="2240">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A Hubble image of a pair of colliding galaxies, with a satellite trail running through it. (credit: Space Telescope Science Institute; NASA)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Throngs of satellites are streaking across the Hubble Space Telescope’s field of view, leaving what look like scratch marks on space photos and hindering scientists’ work. Teeming <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-want-to-save-dark-skies-from-satellite-swarms/">swarms of these satellites</a>, which reflect sunlight and mimic astronomical objects, threaten to gradually <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/as-spacexs-starlink-ramps-up-so-could-light-pollution/">transform the night sky</a> and affect how astronomy can be done.</p>
<p>“We see these satellite trails in Hubble data, and really in all astronomical data, and they’re a bit of a nuisance,” said David Stark, an astronomer at the Space Telescope Science Institute in Baltimore, speaking last week at the <a href="https://aas.org/meetings/aas242">American Astronomical Society</a> conference in Albuquerque, New Mexico. In fact, he said, his team used a new detection method to measure that the rate of satellite trails is <i>doubling</i>. But Stark was presenting his team’s idea for a Band-Aid fix: new software they described in a <a href="https://www.stsci.edu/files/live/sites/www/files/home/hst/instrumentation/acs/documentation/instrument-science-reports-isrs/_documents/isr2208.pdf">recent report</a> that is five to 10 times more sensitive at finding trails than previous software, and then masking them out. “It’s particularly good at finding satellite trails that can be missed by eye,” he said.</p>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right full"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/wired-logo.png"></div>It’s standard procedure for astronomers to try to clean images of “artifacts,” like the effects of cosmic rays hitting Hubble’s camera detectors, or diffraction spikes, which make bright stars look like crosses. Occasionally, a pesky nearby Milky Way star might get in the way of one’s view of a faraway object. The new technique, called Median Radon Transform, examines every linear path across an image at every possible angle. When a particular path aligns with a satellite trail, the system notes a deviation from the average flux—or the brightness at a particular wavelength in a pixel—measured across areas with apparently empty sky. It can spot short streaks, too, but they have to be slightly brighter to be identified, since they cover fewer pixels.</p>
<p>This software then allows astronomers to mask out satellite trails, so that the affected pixels are ignored in their analysis of the data. It’s like dog-earing a few misprinted pages in a book, so that you skip them while studying the rest of the volume.</p>
<p>But it’s better not to lose those pages. When there are multiple exposures of the same field, an astronomer can use additional software tools to completely remove the line from the final combined image. That part of the sky will then appear as it should, though the signal-to-noise ratio in that line’s pixels will be lower than if the satellite had never skimmed in front of the telescope that day. Stark and his team have included their code in a standard software pack called “acstools” that they manage.</p>
<p>Still, this fix has a big limitation: It’s designed for Hubble, which is orbiting 332 miles above the Earth, and it’s less plagued by satellite streaks than observatories on the ground. Ground-based optical telescopes with wide-field imaging—which often don’t take multiple exposures—stand to be far more affected. There have been a few instances already of satellites photobombing images taken by telescopes at the <a href="https://aasnova.org/2022/12/28/selections-from-2022-tracing-satellite-tracks-in-survey-images/">Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory</a> in Chile and the <a href="https://www.astronomy.com/space-exploration/global-astronomy-groups-say-theyre-concerned-about-spacexs-starlink-satellites/">Lowell Observatory</a> in Arizona, for example.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<p>The problem will be much, much worse for the long-awaited National Science Foundation-funded <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-3200-megapixel-camera-has-astronomers-salivating/">Vera Rubin Observatory</a>, which is being assembled in the Chilean Andes and will begin taking images next year. Its incredibly sensitive camera will detect faint and changing objects, like a star going supernova or a near-Earth asteroid, and the telescope will automatically send alerts to astronomers when it spots such things. But the Rubin collaboration has <a href="https://www.lsst.org/content/lsst-statement-regarding-increased-deployment-satellite-constellations#">expressed concern</a> about the possibility of false alerts thanks to light reflecting off of satellites or space junk in orbit and has warned that as many as 30 percent of its images could be affected by satellite streaks. For example, a glint of sunlight off a small piece of insulation shed by a satellite could appear in a telescope image like a flaring star. Unless an astronomer can also measure the light's spectrum, they might be fooled, says John Barentine, a Tucson, Arizona, astronomer who recently <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-023-01904-2">authored a study</a> about light pollution from low Earth orbit objects.</p>
<p>A second problem is that the number of satellite streaks is growing. Stark tested the software on 20 years of data from Hubble’s Advanced Camera for Surveys. While the satellite trails haven’t changed in brightness, their rate has approximately doubled. The team found trails in every three to four hours of Hubble data taken in 2002. But in 2022, satellites photobombed Hubble every one to two hours. That means 5 percent of the images taken 20 years ago were affected, and now it's about 10 percent.</p>
<p>The rate will surely continue rising, says Sandor Kruk, an astronomer at the Max Planck Institute for Extraterrestrial Physics in Munich, Germany. “You expect, as time goes, more streaks in images. It goes proportionately with the number of satellites you have above the observatory,” says Kruk, lead author of a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-023-01903-3">recent study</a> that used crowdsourced classifications and machine learning to track satellite trails in images.</p>
<p>Kruk and his colleagues observed a lower rate, rising from about 2.5 to 5 percent over the past two decades. They found that this trend ramped up rapidly starting in about 2018, around the same time companies began deploying <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/as-spacexs-starlink-ramps-up-so-could-light-pollution/">satellite mega-constellations</a>, connecting hundreds or thousands of them in networks. (Stark and Kruk attribute their studies’ different percentages to using different measuring techniques.)</p>
<p>Those mega-constellations have obvious benefits for their operators. The satellites are smaller and therefore cheaper to produce and launch, and networked services are less vulnerable to disruption, such as by <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/sun-storm-end-civilization/">space weather</a> or <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/analysts-warn-anti-satellite-weapons-have-evolved-beyond-missiles/">anti-satellite weapons</a>. SpaceX’s Starlink makes up the biggest satellite network by far, with some 4,000 in orbit and plans to increase that to 42,000. OneWeb’s constellation has more than 600 satellites, but they’re situated at a higher orbit, lessening the effect on astronomical observations. And Amazon is poised to launch its Project Kuiper this summer, lofting its first broadband-service-providing satellites on the inaugural flight of the United Launch Alliance’s Vulcan Centaur rocket. The company plans to populate that constellation with more than 3,000 satellites.</p>
<p>SpaceX and some other companies have tested possible solutions, like covering a satellite with a thin film to darken it so it reflects less light, or adding a visor to reflect light away from Earth. These limited efforts have fallen far short of the <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-want-to-save-dark-skies-from-satellite-swarms/">International Astronomical Union’s brightness targets</a>, and some of these designs have caused problems for the satellites themselves, by heating them too much or interfering with inter-satellite communication.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/hubble-deployed.jpg"><img alt='Hubble&#039;s deployment by the Space Shuttle Discovery in 1990.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/hubble-deployed-640x480.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/hubble-deployed-1280x960.jpg 2x" alt='Hubble&#039;s deployment by the Space Shuttle Discovery in 1990.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/hubble-deployed.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Hubble's deployment by the Space Shuttle Discovery in 1990.</a> (credit: NASA)</p></div>
<p>A NASA concept to work with its commercial partners to <a href="https://spacenews.com/nasa-and-spacex-to-study-possible-private-hubble-servicing-mission/">boost Hubble</a> to a higher orbit might inadvertently mitigate the photobombing problem. Atmospheric drag has gradually pulled the spacecraft closer to Earth. Nudging it back is intended to extend its lifespan—but would also move it away from a small fraction of passing satellites.</p>
<p>None of that will resolve problems for Earth-based observatories, which have to peer through the whole atmosphere, including all satellite orbits. And Barentine worries that although companies haven’t found any tech fixes yet, they haven’t slowed down the brisk pace of satellite launch. “People in industry have this unerring faith in innovation,” he says, “and my response to that has been: The history of science and technology and the environment is just littered with instances of running headlong into technology we did not understand that created a lot of negative side effects.”</p>
<p><em>This story originally appeared on <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/satellites-keep-photobombing-space-images-astronomers-need-a-fix/">wired.com</a>.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947734&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/satellites-keep-photobombing-spaces-images-astronomers-need-a-fix/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>103</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feds tell automakers not to comply with Mass. “right to repair” law</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947712</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2023/06/feds-tell-automakers-not-to-comply-with-mass-right-to-repair-law/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 12:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[massachusetts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national highway traffic safety administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhtsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[right to repair]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The state's right to repair law requires open access to telematics services.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-960666672-800x542.jpg" alt="A glowing icon of a car with a crossed screwdriver and wrench floats above a human hand"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-960666672-scaled.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1734" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>In 2020, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2020/11/massachusetts-votes-to-extend-right-to-repair-law-to-connected-cars/">voters in Massachusetts chose to extend</a> that state's automotive "right to repair" law to <a href="https://electionstats.state.ma.us/ballot_questions/view/7343/">include telematics and connected car services</a>. But this week, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration told automakers that some of the law's requirements create a real safety problem and that they should be ignored since federal law preempts state law when the two conflict.</p>
<p>Almost all new cars in 2023 contain embedded modems and offer some form of telematics or connected car services. And <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Massachusetts_Question_1,_%22Right_to_Repair_Law%22_Vehicle_Data_Access_Requirement_Initiative_(2020)">the ballot language</a> that passed in Massachusetts requires "manufacturers that sell vehicles with telematics systems in Massachusetts to equip them with a standardized open data platform beginning with model year 2022 that vehicle owners and independent repair facilities may access to retrieve mechanical data and run diagnostics through a mobile-based application."</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2022/01/massachusetts-connected-car-right-to-repair-law-still-on-hold/">There have been attempts</a> by state lawmakers, the auto industry, and NHTSA to tweak the law to create a more reasonable timeline for implementation, but to no avail.</p>
<p>Now, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-tells-automakers-not-comply-with-massachusetts-vehicle-data-law-2023-06-13/">according to Reuters</a>, NHTSA has written to automakers to advise them not to comply with the Massachusetts law. Among its problems are the fact that someone "could utilize such open access to remotely command vehicles to operate dangerously, including attacking multiple vehicles concurrently," and that "open access to vehicle manufacturers’ telematics offerings with the ability to remotely send commands allows for manipulation of systems on a vehicle, including safety-critical functions such as steering, acceleration, or braking."</p>
<p>Faced with this dilemma, it's quite possible the automakers will respond by simply disabling telematics and connected services for customers in the state. Subaru already took that step when it introduced its model year 2022 vehicles, and NHTSA says other OEMs may do the same.</p>
<h2>A federal right to repair law?</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, a bipartisan automotive right to repair law is working its way through Congress. Called <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/6570">the REPAIR Act</a>, it would "provide to a vehicle's owner certain direct, real-time, in-vehicle data generated by the operation of the vehicle that is related to diagnostics, repair, service, wear, and calibration or recalibration of parts and systems of the vehicle."</p>
<p>This bill does acknowledge the cybersecurity risks; if passed, it would require NHTSA to develop data access standards for connected vehicles.</p>
<p><em>Correction: The article as published suggested that the "open" platform called for in the ballot language would be insecure. This has been corrected.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947712&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2023/06/feds-tell-automakers-not-to-comply-with-mass-right-to-repair-law/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>203</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dealmaster: Last-minute savings to celebrate dads and grads</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947435</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/shopping/2023/06/dealmaster-last-minute-savings-to-celebrate-dads-and-grads/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chuong Nguyen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 10:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ars Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dealmaster]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gift ideas and deals for Father's Day and graduation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Whether you're looking to celebrate the father figure in your life or have a new graduate ready for the next chapter, we have deals on last-minute technology, toys, and tools that will make great gifts.</p>
<p>From <a href="https://amzn.to/3p1XBug" target="_blank" rel="noopener">laptops</a> and <a href="https://amzn.to/3qH3vl5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">e-readers</a> to <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOKG5Jlxs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">smartwatches</a> and <a href="https://amzn.to/3Nr1Mcl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">headphones</a>, our curated list of summer deals will help dads and grads stay active, nurture their minds, and enjoy some relaxation. But with Father's Day quickly approaching on Sunday, June 18, and graduation season already well underway, be sure to shop early to ensure your thoughtful gifts arrive in time for the festivity.</p>
<h2>Kindle e-readers</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/DSC04483.jpg"><img alt='Amazon&#039;s Kindle Oasis. '  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/DSC04483-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/DSC04483-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Amazon&#039;s Kindle Oasis. ' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/DSC04483.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Amazon's Kindle Oasis. </a> </p></div>
<ul>
<li>Amazon Kindle Paperwhite Signature Edition $145 (was $190) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qH3vl5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Amazon Kindle Paperwhite Kids for $100 (was $160) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43CjYpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Amazon Kindle Paperwhite for $110 (was $140) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3CowVqL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Amazon Kindle (2022) for $80 (was $100) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3p1Djkx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Amazon Kindle Kids (2022) for $85 (was $120) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43TlaUQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Laptops and tablets</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/thinkpadsAMD4.jpg"><img alt='Those who want AMD power in a ThinkPad shell now have a few new options.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/thinkpadsAMD4-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/thinkpadsAMD4-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Those who want AMD power in a ThinkPad shell now have a few new options.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/thinkpadsAMD4.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Those who want AMD power in a ThinkPad shell now have a few new options.</a> (credit: Valentina Palladino)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Apple MacBook Air (15-inch, M2) for $1,250 (was $1,299) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43R3au8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Apple MacBook Air (13-inch, M1) for $849 (was $999) at <a href="https://amzn.to/463lYsg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Apple MacBook Pro (16-inch, M2) for $2,249 (was $2,499) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3p1XBug" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Apple iPad 10th Gen for $400 (was $449) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3PaptqF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Apple iPad Air 5th Gen for $500 (was $599) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3Paixd1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Apple iPad Pro (12.9-inch, M2) for $1,049 (was $1,099) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3NqJ2JZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon Gen 10 (14-inch, Intel Core i5-1240P) for $1,309 with THINK72FLASHDEAL coupon (was $2,909) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWO96AmIQN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon Gen 10 (14-inch, Intel Core i7-1260P) for $1,548 with THINK72FLASHDEAL coupon (was $3,439) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPdgzht3M" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad P16 (16-inch, Intel Core i9-12900HX and RTX A4500) for $2,839 (was $4,260) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPbvffhsh" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad P16 (16-inch, Intel Core i9-12950HX and RTX A4500) for $2,679 (was $6,699) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPe8ImgKv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad P16 (16-inch, Intel Core i7-12800HX and RTX A1000) for $1,449 (was $3,619) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPjBh0ANX" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad P1 Gen 5 (16-inch, Intel Core i7-12800H and RTX 3070 Ti) for $2,139 (was $5,339) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPgzX6qYe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad P1 Gen 5 (16-inch, Intel Core i9-12900H and RTX 3080 Ti) for $2,689 (was $6,729) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPh4aAAfK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo ThinkPad P1 Gen 5 (16-inch, Intel Core i7-12800H and RTX A4500) for $2,439 (was $6,099) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPkXBd7vL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo Legion Pro 5i Gen 8 (16-inch, Intel Core i5-12500HX and RTX 4050) for $1,220 (was $1,480) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPmJIDYA6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo Legion Slim 5i Gen 8 (16-inch, Intel Core i7-13700H and RTX 4060) for $1,400 (was $1,630) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPolSVRlO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo Slim 7i (14-inch, Intel Core i5-1340P) for $774 with JUNEDEALS coupon (was $1,180) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPpzvi0AS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo IdeaPad Slim (15-inch, AMD Ryzen 3 7330u) for $420 with JUNEDEALS coupon (was $650) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPq7Fczzu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Lenovo Tab P11 Pro Gen 2 for $336 (was $430) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWPsE60u13" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lenovo</a></li>
<li>Dell XPS 15 (15-inch, Intel Core i7-12700H, RTX 3050) for $1,099 (was $1,899) at <a href="https://tinyurl.com/2p8sdxc8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dell</a></li>
<li>Dell XPS 13 Plus (13-inch, Intel Core i5-1240P) for $899 (was $1,399) at <a href="https://tinyurl.com/2p934dzm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dell</a></li>
<li>Dell XPS 17 (17-inch, Intel Core i5-12500H) for $1,299 (was $1,949) at <a href="https://tinyurl.com/5besfd2u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dell</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Toys</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Lego-X-Wing-Starfighter-Star-Wars.jpg"><img alt='Star Wars X-Wing Starfighter set from Lego.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Lego-X-Wing-Starfighter-Star-Wars-640x360.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Lego-X-Wing-Starfighter-Star-Wars.jpg 2x" alt='Star Wars X-Wing Starfighter set from Lego.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Lego-X-Wing-Starfighter-Star-Wars.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Star Wars X-Wing Starfighter set from Lego.</a> (credit: LEGO)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Swatch Jumpsuit NASA watch for $120 (was $135) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3JfvbDV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Technic McLaren Senna GTR for $40 (was $50) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X6vjeK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Architecture Paris Skyline for $40 (was $50) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3NpmzNs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Architecture Statue of Liberty for $96 (was $120) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3Pbsrv9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Technic Formula E Porsche 99X for $40 (was $50) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43Bze5P" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Star Wars The Mandalorian Helmet for $57 (was $70) at <a href="https://amzn.to/45YNmHM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Star Wars Luke Skywalker Red 5 Helmet for $57 (was $70) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3J6GazG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Brickheadz Star Wars The Mandalorian and The Child for $16 (was $20) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3PaBEUt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Star Wars The Mandalorian Series The Child for $72 (was $90) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3N4CS0W" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Star Wars Luke Skywalker X-Wing Fighter for $40 (was $50) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3p9KJCe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Architecture The White House for $90 (was $100) at <a href="https://amzn.to/4631cJm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Lego Star Wars The Mandalorian N-1 Straighter for $48 (was $60) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qH5Xbe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Tools</h2>
<ul>
<li>DeWalt 20V Max 7-tool combo kit for $599 (was $819) at <a href="https://amzn.to/462tYd6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>DeWalt 20V Max XR cordless drill, impact driver bare tool for $99 (was $149) at <a href="https://amzn.to/42IzgqZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>DeWalt 20V Max orbital sander and oscillating tool for $229 (was $349) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43BSEr8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>DeWalt 20V Max miter saw for $299 (was $369) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3P8x0pW" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>DeWalt thickness planer for $599 (was $799) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43DK4rM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>DeWalt 20V Max 3-tool combo kit for $329 (was $369) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43YFowj" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Gearwrench 114-piece SAE/metric ratcheting tap and die set for $211 (was $236) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3JbtbNb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Gearwrench 20-piece screwdriver set for $70 (was $82) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43TMVN9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Crescent 11-inch automotive wrench for $34 (was $65) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X3Z3c2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Gearwrench 12-piece snap ring plier set for $103 (was $165) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3CpvIiL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Gearwrench 44-piece master combination wrench set for $202 (was $518) at <a href="https://amzn.to/42Du2wV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Gearwrench 239-piece BMC mechanics tool set for $200 (was $240) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3Pa1wQb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Gearwrench 16-piece ratcheting flex combination wrench set for $196 (was $230) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X2wj3A" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Crescent 229-piece tool set with storage chest for $199 (was $253) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3NBJCVH" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Gearwrench 312-piece master tool set for $690 (was $816) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qF8ti7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Sonos</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/sub-living-books.jpg"><img alt='The Sonos Sub subwoofer.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/sub-living-books-640x523.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/sub-living-books-1280x1045.jpg 2x" alt='The Sonos Sub subwoofer.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/sub-living-books.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Sonos Sub subwoofer.</a> (credit: Sonos)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Sonos Arc Soundbar for $719 (was $900) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQlMUTSrT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Sonos Beam Gen 2 for $399 (was $499) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQmVTE8gN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Sonos One SL for $159 (was $200) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQn50P6MJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Sonos Sub Gen 3 Wireless Subwoofer for $639 (was $799) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQpdO9Oxc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Sonos Move Portable Wi-Fi and Bluetooth Speaker for $299 (was $400) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQqfTBT81" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Sonos Ray Soundbar for $223 (was $280) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQrjdLcRZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Trackers</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AirTag-4-pack.png"><img alt='AirTags also come in packs of four for $99.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AirTag-4-pack-640x461.png" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AirTag-4-pack-1280x922.png 2x" alt='AirTags also come in packs of four for $99.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/AirTag-4-pack.png"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">AirTags also come in packs of four for $99.</a> (credit: Samuel Axon)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Apple AirTag 4-pack for $89 (was $99) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3JcPjXr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Pebblebee Card &amp; Clip Multipack (compatible with Find My) for $100 (was $120) at <a href="https://fave.co/3oUZwRt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pebblebee</a></li>
<li>Pebblebee Card &amp; 2x Clip (compatible with Find My) for $80 (was $90) at <a href="https://fave.co/3oU29CR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pebblebee</a></li>
<li>Chipolo Card Spot 2x (compatible with Find My) for $60 (was $70) at <a href="https://fave.co/3CuiFNb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chipolo</a></li>
<li>Chipolo Card Spot 4x (compatible with Find My) for $112 (was $140) at <a href="https://fave.co/3Ns1imj" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chipolo</a></li>
<li>Chipolo Spot Bundle (compatible with Find My) for $77 (was $91) at <a href="https://fave.co/3oV0ey7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chipolo</a></li>
<li>Chipolo One Spot 4x (compatible with Find My) for $79 (was $112) at <a href="https://fave.co/43ABo5n" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chipolo</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Headphones and microphones</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-6.jpg"><img alt='Sony&#039;s WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-6-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-6-1280x853.jpg 2x" alt='Sony&#039;s WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/sony-6.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Sony's WH-1000XM3 noise-cancelling headphones.</a> (credit: Jeff Dunn)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Beats Fit Pro earbuds for $160 (was $200) at <a href="https://amzn.to/42BS3UY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Beats Studio Buds for $100 (was $150) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3P92qMQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Beats Powerbeats Pro earbuds for $160 (was $250) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3p0GDMU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Apple AirPods Max for $450 (was $549) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qHYOHJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Apple AirPods Pro 2nd Generation for $200 (was $249) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3Nr1Mcl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Sony WH-1000XM5 headphones for $348 (was $400) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X2jc2e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Sony WF-1000XM4 earbuds for $198 (was $280) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3CoFgKO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Sony LinkBuds earbuds for $128 (was $180) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43WZiId" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Sony LinkBuds S earbuds for $128 (was $200) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3JcoVwC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Sony WH-1000XM4 headphones for $278 (was $348) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3p5XFcj" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Bose 700 wireless noise-canceling headphones for $299 (was $379) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43zuA8r" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Bose QuietComfort 45 headphones for $279 (was $329) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3PcJgps" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Logitech Blue Yeti Nano for $80 (was $100) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X6UX39" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Logitech Blue Yeti for $90 (was $130) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X4d7lP" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Bang &amp; Olufsen Beoplay EQ for $165 (was $175) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3NrlViz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Bang &amp; Olufsen Beoplay EX for $380 (was $400) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X1ct8R" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Bang &amp; Olufsen Beoplay H4 for $170 (was $200) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qDlo4a" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Smartphones</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pixel7-8.jpg"><img alt='The Pixel 7 Pro.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pixel7-8-640x390.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pixel7-8-1280x780.jpg 2x" alt='The Pixel 7 Pro.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pixel7-8.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Pixel 7 Pro.</a> (credit: Ron Amadeo / Ars Technica)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Google Pixel 7 Pro from $700 (was $900) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qIfQFG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Google Pixel 6a for $300 (was $349) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X1FZeH" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Google Pixel 7 with $100 Amazon gift card for $599 (was $699) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3NoOm0C" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>OnePlus 11 5G for $699 (was $799) at <a href="https://fave.co/3X7Y7Ui" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus</a></li>
<li>OnePlus 10 Pro 5G for $479 (was $799) at <a href="https://fave.co/3NoOZr0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus</a></li>
<li>OnePlus 10T 5G for $429 (was $649) at <a href="https://fave.co/43CYt7x" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnePlus</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Smartwatches and wearables</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Garmin-Forerunner-945-LTE-55-Hands-on-Ars-Technica-6.jpg"><img alt='The Forerunner 945 LTE (left) doesn&#039;t need your phone to contact emergency services or share your routes with contacts, though the Forerunner 55 (right) can do the former with a phone nearby.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Garmin-Forerunner-945-LTE-55-Hands-on-Ars-Technica-6-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Garmin-Forerunner-945-LTE-55-Hands-on-Ars-Technica-6-1280x854.jpg 2x" alt='The Forerunner 945 LTE (left) doesn&#039;t need your phone to contact emergency services or share your routes with contacts, though the Forerunner 55 (right) can do the former with a phone nearby.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Garmin-Forerunner-945-LTE-55-Hands-on-Ars-Technica-6.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Forerunner 945 LTE (left) doesn't need your phone to contact emergency services or share your routes with contacts, though the Forerunner 55 (right) can do the former with a phone nearby.</a> (credit: Corey Gaskin)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Samsung Galaxy Watch5 Pro for $400 (was $450) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOE73f62C" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a> | <a href="https://amzn.to/3PamHlq" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 Classic 46 mm for $200 (was $380) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOG9zZaEN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 40 mm for $180 (was $200) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOIqdN1kM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Apple Watch SE 2nd Generation 44 m for $249 (was $279) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOJGMIZ1F" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Apple Watch Series 8 4 5mm for $359 (was $429) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOKG5Jlxs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Amazfit Bip 3 Pro 42.9 mm for $60 (was $70) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOMdZg6ZX" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Garmin Forerunner 45 42 mm for $130 (was $170) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWONAErLDN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Fitbit Charge 5 Advanced for $120 (was $150) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOORy48z4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Fitbit Inspire 3 for $80 (was $100) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOQDK8y92" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Garmin Fenix 7X Sapphire Solar 51 mm for $800 (was $1,000) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWORDLbTRa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Garmin Fenix 7 Solar 47 mm for $600 (was $800) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOS7YLzIh" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Garmin Fenix 7S 42 mm for $500 (was $700) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOUcpuBI8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Garmin Epic Gen 2 47 mm for $800 (was $1,000) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOVpGGDwq" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Garmin Venu 2 Plus 43 mm for $400 (was $450) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOWlVt7Dr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Oura Ring Gen3 Heritage for $409 (was $449) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOX5p7Ibk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Oura Ring Gen3 Horizon for $409 (was $449) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWOZp2enV5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Google Pixel Watch for $300 (was $350) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQiYkPsJ3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
<li>Google Pixel Watch LTE for $330 (was $400) at <a href="https://howl.me/cjWQjLAVz4V" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best Buy</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Home, kitchen, and personal care</h2>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/37.jpg"><img alt='The Roomba Combo j7+. Sick spoiler, bro! Wait, that&#039;s a mop?!'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/37-640x360.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/37-1280x720.jpg 2x" alt='The Roomba Combo j7+. Sick spoiler, bro! Wait, that&#039;s a mop?!' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/37.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The Roomba Combo j7+. Sick spoiler, bro! Wait, that's a mop?!</a> (credit: Roomba)</p></div>
<ul>
<li>Braun Hair Clippers Series 7 7390 for $60 (was $70) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3N7mDjy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Braun Electric Razor Series 9 Pro 9419s for $250 (was $300) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3Cvq2ni" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Braun All-in-One Style Kit Series 9 9440 for $100 (was $130) at <a href="https://amzn.to/440E0tn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Braun Electric Razor Series 7 7075cc for $127 (was $160) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3P6mv6v" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Braun Electric Razor Series 9 Pro 9460cc for $270 (was $330) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3NoAjrV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Philips Norelco Shaver 3800 for $65 (was $80) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3Pd07IL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Philips Norelco Shaver 7800 for $130 (was $160) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3X60FSF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Philips Norelco Shaver 9800 for $215 (was $260) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qLiD0z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Philips Norelco Shaver X7500 for $72 (was $90) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3Xb3h1O" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>OXO Brew 8 Cup Coffee Maker for $140 (was $200) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43TqmrO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Ninja CFN601 Espresso &amp; Coffee Barista System for $200 (was $250) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43Y8hZw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>iRobot Roomba Combo j7+ robot vacuum and mop with dock for $799 (was $1,100) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43YE5Oi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>iRobot Roomba i3+ EVO with dock for $379 (was $549) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3qFXXau" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Chargers, cables, and organizers</h2>
<ul>
<li>Ugreen 65 W GAN charger for $35 (was $50) at <a href="https://amzn.to/43WSiuR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Safuel 2-pack USB-C to USB-C 100 W braided cable (6.6-feet) for $6 (was $10) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3p17Y1w" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Soulwit cable management kit for $12 after coupon (was $15) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3oYV9Vr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
<li>Must Silicone cable ties for $8 (was $11) at <a href="https://amzn.to/3N5WG3V" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Ars Technica may earn compensation for sales from links on this post through <a href="https://arstechnica.com/affiliate-link-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-uri="4c776bd3d2b303f3138d656b48f6862b">affiliate programs</a>.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947435&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/shopping/2023/06/dealmaster-last-minute-savings-to-celebrate-dads-and-grads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3D muscle reconstruction shows 3.2 million-year-old “Lucy” walked upright</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947108</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/3d-muscle-reconstruction-shows-3-2-million-year-old-lucy-walked-upright/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 23:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient hominins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biomechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computational modeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolutionary biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human evolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucy fossil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleoanthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleontology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Lucy’s muscles suggest that she was as proficient at bipedalism as we are."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[





<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<figure class="video ars-wp-video">
    <div class="wrapper ars-wp-video-wrapper" style="padding-bottom: 56.122448979592%;">
        <video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-1947108-1" width="980" height="550" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/LucyMuscle2.mp4?_=1" />3D reconstruction of lower limb muscles of <em>Australopithecus afarensis</em> fossil AL 288-1, aka "Lucy." Credit: Ashleigh Wiseman</video>    </div>
        <figcaption class="caption">
        <div class="caption-text">3D reconstruction of lower limb muscles of <em>Australopithecus afarensis</em> fossil AL 288-1, aka "Lucy." Credit: Ashleigh Wiseman </div>
    </figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>One of the most famous fossils in human evolutionary history is known as "<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lucy_(Australopithecus)">Lucy</a>," who belonged to an extinct species called <em>Australopithecus afarensis</em>—an early relative of <em>Homo sapiens</em> who was among the first hominins to walk upright. But scientists have long debated the extent of her bipedalism. Now a 3D digital re-creation of Lucy's muscular anatomy, combined with computer simulations, has reaffirmed that she was quite capable of walking fully erect. The results appeared in a new paper published in the journal Royal Society Open Science.</p>
<p>“Lucy’s ability to walk upright can only be known by reconstructing the path and space that a muscle occupies within the body,” <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/992054">said author Ashleigh Wiseman</a>, an archaeologist at Cambridge University. “We are now the only animal that can stand upright with straight knees. Lucy’s muscles suggest that she was as proficient at bipedalism as we are, while possibly also being at home in the trees.”</p>
<p>Lucy's remains were found in 1974 in Ethiopia at a site called Hadar. Several paleoarchaeologists—including Donald Johanson, Mary Leakey, and Yves Coppens—began surveying the site for signs of fossils relating to the origin of humans. The first interesting find occurred in November 1971, when Johanson found a fossilized upper shinbone and, nearby, the lower end of a femur. Now known as AL 129-1 and dating back more than 3 million years, the angle of the knee joint indicated this was a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hominini">hominin</a> (now known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Australopithecus_afarensis"><em>Australopithecus afarensi</em>s</a>) capable of walking upright.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy-trio.jpg"><img alt='(left) Reconstruction of the fossil skeleton of &quot;Lucy.&quot; (center) Lucy skeleton reconstruction at the Cleveland Museum of Natural History. (right) Reconstruction of Lucy at the National Museum of Anthropology in Mexico.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy-trio-640x427.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy-trio.jpg 2x" alt='(left) Reconstruction of the fossil skeleton of &quot;Lucy.&quot; (center) Lucy skeleton reconstruction at the Cleveland Museum of Natural History. (right) Reconstruction of Lucy at the National Museum of Anthropology in Mexico.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy-trio.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">(left) Reconstruction of the fossil skeleton of "Lucy." (center) Lucy skeleton reconstruction at the Cleveland Museum of Natural History. (right) Reconstruction of Lucy at the National Museum of Anthropology in Mexico.</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">120/Andrew Bardwell/Ernesto Lazaros /CC BY-SA 4.0</a>)</p></div>
<p>But the really significant find occurred on November 24, 1974, when Johanson and fellow expedition member Tom Gray decided to check out the bottom of a small gully. Johanson spotted an arm bone fragment, then a skull fragment, then part of a femur. Further exploration over the next few weeks yielded many more bones, including vertebrae, part of a pelvis, ribs, and jaw fragments, all belonging to the same individual hominin. All told there were several hundred fossilized bone pieces constituting 40 percent of a complete female skeleton. This was "Lucy," aka AL 288-1, named after the 1967 Beatles tune "Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds," which had been played loudly and repeatedly on a camp tape recorder.</p>
<p>Once all the pieces were assembled, scientists were able to reconstruct Lucy, revealing that she stood about 1.1 meters (3 feet, 7 inches) tall and weighed about 29 kilograms (64 pounds). Her brain was small, like a chimpanzee's, but her pelvis and leg bones (including a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genu_valgum">valgus knee</a>) looked almost identical to modern humans, indicating that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Australopithecus_afarensis"><em>Australopithecus afarensis</em></a> was fully bipedal, i.e., stood upright and walked erect.</p>
<p>How Lucy died is a matter of heated scientific debate. A controversial <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature19332">2016 paper</a> suggested that a careful analysis of her bones reveals how she died—by falling to her death from a very tall tree—although other scientists (including Johanson) thought the evidence was thin at best. As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2016/08/doubts-about-whether-ancient-hominin-lucy-fell-to-her-death-3-18-million-years-ago/">we reported</a> at the time, University of Texas-Austin anthropologist John Kappelman and his team did a complete X-ray CT scan on Lucy's bones, allowing them to create high-resolution 3D renders and 3D printouts of her skeleton.</p>
<p>By comparing the way her bones had fragmented with contemporary X-rays from people who fell, they concluded that the fragmentation of her leg bone was "green," that is, it took place right before she died. Specifically, the joint in Lucy's leg suffered from extreme compression of the type you'd expect in somebody who fell on their feet from a great height, perhaps out of a local tree where nests might be as many as 23 meters off the ground. However, skeptics pointed out that the process of fossilization often fragments bones in exactly the way that Lucy's bones are broken, and animals fossilized at the same time as Lucy have similar fractures.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy3.jpg"><img alt='Polygonal muscles of &quot;Lucy&quot; compared to 3D muscles of a human.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy3-640x757.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy3.jpg 2x" alt='Polygonal muscles of &quot;Lucy&quot; compared to 3D muscles of a human.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/lucy3.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Polygonal muscles of "Lucy" compared to 3D muscles of a human.</a> (credit: Ashleigh Wiseman)</p></div>
<p>There has also been significant debate over precisely how frequently and efficiently Lucy and her fellow <em>Australopithecus afarensis</em> walked. Specifically, Lucy had a much wider pelvis and shorter legs than a human, which some scholars have argued would have affected her gait. A consensus has begun to emerge in recent years in favor of a fully erect gait, rather than more of a crouching waddle, similar to chimpanzees. Wiseman decided to use computer simulations and muscle modeling in hopes of shedding further light on the issue.</p>
<p>She was inspired in part by <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-07074-x">the work</a> of paleobiologist Oliver Demuth, who creates biomechanical <a href="https://dawndinos.com/musculoskeletal-modelling-and-simulation-of-movement/">3D musculoskeletal models</a> of <a href="https://dawndinos.com/extinct-archosaurs/">extinct archosaurs</a>. Extinct species mostly leave behind fossilized bones and skeletons, and while much can be learned from those remains, one needs to find a way to re-create the overlaying muscles to understand the biomechanics of how a given species moved. Demuth first used the limb anatomy of existing species to create 3D musculoskeletal models of known animals and then simulated movements like walking running, jumping, or standing. Then he extended and adapted those models to extinct animals.</p>
<p>Wiseman followed a similar course of action for her own work re-creating Lucy's musculature. First, she relied upon MRI scans and CT scans of adult female and male humans to map muscle paths and create a feasible 3D digital musculoskeletal model. Next, she used recently published open source virtual models of the Lucy fossil to put her skeleton back together, showing how each joint could move and rotate. Finally, she layered the muscles on top, relying on her map of human muscle paths, augmented by a few telltale traces of scarring from where muscle had once connected to Lucy's fossilized bones.</p>
<figure class="video ars-wp-video">
    <div class="wrapper ars-wp-video-wrapper" style="padding-bottom: 56.122448979592%;">
        <video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-1947108-2" width="980" height="550" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/LucyMuscle1.mp4?_=2" />3D polygonal model, guided by imaging scan data and muscle scarring, reconstructing the lower limb muscles of the <em>Australopithecus afarensis</em> fossil AL 288-1, aka "Lucy." Credit: Ashleigh Wiseman</video>    </div>
        <figcaption class="caption">
        <div class="caption-text">3D polygonal model, guided by imaging scan data and muscle scarring, reconstructing the lower limb muscles of the <em>Australopithecus afarensis</em> fossil AL 288-1, aka "Lucy." Credit: Ashleigh Wiseman </div>
    </figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>The resulting model included 36 muscles in each leg. Per Wiseman, Lucy had much larger calves and thighs than modern humans; the major muscles were more than twice the size. Fully 74 percent of Lucy's thigh consisted of muscle tissue compared to 50 percent in humans. Wiseman concluded that Lucy's knee extensor muscles would allow for sufficient leverage to straighten the knee joints like modern humans, thereby enabling Lucy to walk upright, as well as performing a range of other motions similar to chimpanzees and bonobos.</p>
<p>These findings add further evidence to the emerging scientific consensus, but Wiseman cautioned that this is not definitive proof that Lucy could walk erect frequently and efficiently. "Lucy likely walked and moved in a way that we do not see in any living species today,” <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/992054?">she said</a>. “<em>Australopithecus afarensis</em> would have roamed areas of open wooded grassland as well as more dense forests in East Africa around 3 to 4 million years ago. These reconstructions of Lucy’s muscles suggest that she would have been able to exploit both habitats effectively.”</p>
<p>DOI: Royal Society Open Science, 2023. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.230356">10.1098/rsos.230356</a>  (<a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2010/03/dois-and-their-discontents-1.ars">About DOIs</a>).</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947108&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/06/3d-muscle-reconstruction-shows-3-2-million-year-old-lucy-walked-upright/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI rolls out big chatbot API upgrades for developers</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947545</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/06/openai-rolls-out-big-chatbot-api-upgrades-for-developers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 21:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[API]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPT-3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPT-3.5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gpt-3.5-turbo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPT-4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[API updates include 4x larger conversation memory for GPT-3.5 and function calling.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/chatgpt_superhero-800x450.jpg" alt="An AI-generated chatbot flying like a superhero."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/chatgpt_superhero.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="675" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> An AI-generated chatbot flying like a superhero. (credit: Stable Diffusion / OpenAI)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>On Tuesday, OpenAI <a href="https://openai.com/blog/function-calling-and-other-api-updates">announced</a> a sizable update to its large language model API offerings (including <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/03/openai-announces-gpt-4-its-next-generation-ai-language-model/">GPT-4</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/03/chatgpt-and-whisper-apis-debut-allowing-devs-to-integrate-them-into-apps/">gpt-3.5-turbo</a>), including a new function-calling capability, significant cost reductions, and a 16,000 token context window option for the gpt-3.5-turbo model.</p>

<p>In large language models (LLMs), the "context window" is like a short-term memory that stores the contents of the prompt input or, in the case of a chatbot, the entire contents of the ongoing conversation. In language models, increasing context size has become a technological race, with Anthropic <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/05/anthropics-claude-ai-can-now-digest-an-entire-book-like-the-great-gatsby-in-seconds/">recently announcing</a> a 75,000-token context window option for its Claude language model. In addition, OpenAI has developed a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/03/openai-announces-gpt-4-its-next-generation-ai-language-model/">32,000-token</a> version of GPT-4, but it is not yet publicly available.</p>
<p>Along those lines, OpenAI just introduced a new 16,000 context window version of gpt-3.5-turbo, called, unsurprisingly, "gpt-3.5-turbo-16k," which allows a prompt to be up to 16,000 tokens in length. With four times the context length of the standard 4,000 version, gpt-3.5-turbo-16k can process around 20 pages of text in a single request. This is a considerable boost for developers requiring the model to process and generate responses for larger chunks of text.</p>
<p>As covered in detail in the announcement post, OpenAI listed at least four other major new changes to its GPT APIs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Introduction of function-calling feature in the <a href="https://platform.openai.com/docs/guides/gpt">Chat Completions API</a></li>
<li>Improved and "more steerable" versions of GPT-4 and gpt-3.5-turbo</li>
<li>A 75 percent price cut on the "ada" embeddings model</li>
<li>A 25 percent price reduction on input tokens for gpt-3.5-turbo.</li>
</ul>
<p>With function calling, developers can now more easily build chatbots capable of calling external tools, converting natural language into external API calls, or making database queries. For example, it can convert prompts such as, "Email Anya to see if she wants to get coffee next Friday" into a function call like, "send_email(to: string, body: string)." In particular, this feature will also allow for consistent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON">JSON</a>-formatted output, which API users previously had difficulty generating.</p>

<p>Regarding "steerability," which is a fancy term for the process of getting the LLM to behave the way you want it to, OpenAI says its new "gpt-3.5-turbo-0613" model will include "more reliable steerability via the system message." The system message in the API is a special directive prompt that tells the model how to behave, such as "You are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/for-reasons-no-one-can-fathom-mcdonalds-has-released-a-new-game-boy-color-game/">Grimace</a>. You only talk about milkshakes."</p>
<p>In addition to the functional improvements, OpenAI is offering substantial cost reductions. Notably, the price of the popular gpt-3.5-turbo’s input tokens has been reduced by 25 percent. This means developers can now use this model for approximately $0.0015 per 1,000 input tokens and $0.002 per 1,000 output tokens, equating to roughly 700 pages per dollar. The gpt-3.5-turbo-16k model is priced at $0.003 per 1,000 input tokens and $0.004 per 1,000 output tokens.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/how_gpt_models_work.jpg"><img alt='A diagram showing how GPT conversational language model prompting works.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/how_gpt_models_work-640x522.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/how_gpt_models_work.jpg 2x" alt='A diagram showing how GPT conversational language model prompting works.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/how_gpt_models_work.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">A diagram showing how GPT conversational language model prompting works.</a> (credit: Benj Edwards / Ars Technica)</p></div>
<p>Further, OpenAI is offering a massive 75 percent cost reduction for its "<a href="https://openai.com/blog/new-and-improved-embedding-model">text-embedding-ada-002</a>" embeddings model, which is more esoteric in use than its conversational brethren. An embeddings model is like a translator for computers, turning words and concepts into a numerical language that machines can understand, which is important for tasks like searching text and suggesting relevant content.</p>

<p>Since OpenAI keeps updating its models, the old ones won't be around forever. Today, the company also announced it is beginning the deprecation process for some earlier versions of these models, including gpt-3.5-turbo-0301 and gpt-4-0314. The company says that developers can continue to use these models until September 13, after which the older models will no longer be accessible.</p>
<p>It's worth noting that OpenAI's GPT-4 API is still <a href="https://openai.com/waitlist/gpt-4-api">locked behind a waitlist</a> and yet widely available.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947545&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/06/openai-rolls-out-big-chatbot-api-upgrades-for-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lead admin of child sex abuse website pleads guilty, faces 20 years to life</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947631</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/lead-admin-of-child-sex-abuse-website-pleads-guilty-faces-20-years-to-life/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 21:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child pornography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child sexual abuse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DOJ: Website had "section devoted to the sexual abuse of infants and toddlers."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-519951874-800x537.jpg" alt="The bars of a jail cell are pictured along with a man's hand turning a key in the lock of the cell door."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-519951874-scaled.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1718" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: Getty Images | Charles O'Rear)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>A man described as the lead administrator of a child sexual abuse website pleaded guilty to engaging in a child exploitation enterprise and faces a sentence of at least 20 years and possibly life in prison. The website was "dedicated to the advertisement and distribution of images and videos depicting child sexual abuse," the federal government said.</p>
<p>William Michael Spearman, a 57-year-old from Alabama, pleaded guilty yesterday in US District Court for the Southern District of Florida, the US Department of Justice <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/man-pleads-guilty-running-child-sexual-abuse-website">announced</a>. Four other defendants were previously convicted of crimes related to "their involvement with the same website," the DOJ said.</p>
<p>"The website included a section devoted to the sexual abuse of infants and toddlers, a section devoted to images and videos depicting children being subjected to pain and torture, and a section devoted to avoiding detection by law enforcement," the DOJ said. "As the lead administrator, Spearman managed numerous 'staff' members, directed them how to help run the site, recommended other users for promotion, kept records of child pornography files advertised and distributed over the site, presided over staff meetings, praised and scolded users, and counseled users and other managers about the function and expectations of the website. Spearman also advertised and distributed images over the website."</p>
<p>Spearman is scheduled to be sentenced on August 31. He "faces a mandatory minimum sentence of 20 years in prison and a maximum sentence of life in prison," the announcement said.</p>
<h2>Website had 100+ registered users</h2>
<p>FBI Special Agent David Backlund described details of the case in a November 2022 <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.623852/gov.uscourts.flsd.623852.1.0.pdf">affidavit</a>. The website—referred to as "target website" in the affidavit—had at least 100 registered members who accessed their accounts with passwords, Backlund wrote.</p>
<p>Website users "traffic in child pornography images and videos via the posting of web links within messages," the affidavit said. "These links allow a user to navigate to another website, such as a file-hosting website, where images and/or videos were stored in order to download these images and videos. When posting the links, users of the target website also generally include descriptive text that provides information about the sexual acts and age and gender of the child victim depicted in the linked-to child pornography files. The target website provides rules that instruct users to share child pornography in this manner."</p>
<p>Defendant Selwyn Rosenstein was previously convicted of conspiracy to advertise child pornography, five counts of advertisement of child pornography, and possession of child pornography, the DOJ said. He was sentenced to 28 years in prison and ordered to pay $85,000 in restitution to victims.</p>
<p>Defendants Gregory Good, Robert Boyles, and Matthew Garrell were convicted of conspiracy to advertise child pornography and conspiracy to distribute child pornography. Their sentencing hearings are scheduled for August.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Shared URLs led to sexual abuse images</h2>
<p>The FBI found that Spearman "has, on more than three occasions, shared thousands of URL links to child pornography via the target website that were accessible to more than 10 other target website users," the affidavit said.</p>
<p>The affidavit describes three occasions in which Spearman shared a "collection of links" to images of child sexual abuse, and in each case the affidavit details one of the links from the larger collection. One link allegedly shared by Spearman led to "child pornography files [that] depicted a young girl being sexually abused by an older woman," the affidavit said.</p>
<p>Another link shared by Spearman led to an album containing 21 images showing prepubescent girls performing sex acts on men, the affidavit said.</p>
<p>Spearman is also said to have shared a link that "redirected to another website that contained 79 images of a known female victim who was estimated to be between the ages of seven and nine at the time of the abuse."</p>
<h2>Home search found laptop and thumb drive</h2>
<p>The FBI executed a search warrant at Spearman's residence in Madison, Alabama, in early November. "During the execution of the search warrant, after being advised of his rights, Spearman admitted to FBI agents that he was the subject user on the target website," Backlund's affidavit said. "He stated that he had been on the target website since approximately 2018, had shared child pornography over the site, and had taken steps to manage the site. He also stated that he maintained child pornography on devices in his residence."</p>
<p>FBI agents searched a laptop in Spearman's garage and found evidence of Spearman accessing the target website and a related website "that is also dedicated to child sexual exploitation," the affidavit said. Agents also found a thumb drive containing "a large volume of child pornography," Backlund wrote.</p>
<p>Spearman's guilty plea to the count of engaging in a child exploitation enterprise is conditional and could be withdrawn if his pending motion to suppress evidence is granted.</p>
<p>"The defendant's motion alleged the warrantless seizure of his Internet Protocol address (IP address) and sought to suppress all physical evidence seized and statements as fruit of the poisonous tree as a result of the execution of a search warrant of his residence and person," according to the <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.623852/gov.uscourts.flsd.623852.148.0.pdf">plea agreement</a> filed by the US Attorney's Office for the Southern District of Florida. "This office and the defendant agree that an order suppressing the subject evidence, or an appeal granting such relief, is case dispositive."</p>
<p>As part of the plea agreement, the US Attorney's Office agreed to seek dismissal of two of the three counts in the <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.623852/gov.uscourts.flsd.623852.12.0.pdf">indictment</a> of Spearman. The to-be-dismissed counts are conspiracy to advertise child pornography and conspiracy to distribute child pornography. Still, the plea agreement says the defendant understands that the court must impose a sentence of at least 20 years in prison "and may impose a statutory maximum term of life imprisonment."</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947631&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/06/lead-admin-of-child-sex-abuse-website-pleads-guilty-faces-20-years-to-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>111</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reddit CEO assures employees that API pricing protests haven’t hurt revenue</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947571</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/reddit-ceo-assures-employees-that-api-protests-havent-hurt-revenue/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 21:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[API]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Furor "will pass," Huffman says in internal memo reportedly viewed by The Verge.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-1232875671-800x531.jpg" alt="In this photo illustration the American social news"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/GettyImages-1232875671-scaled.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1700" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/in-this-photo-illustration-the-american-social-news-news-photo/1232875671">Reddit</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>There are<a href="https://www.twitch.tv/reddark_247"> nearly 8,500 subreddits</a> that are private or read-only right now in protest over Reddit's upcoming API price hike. The protest started on June 12, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/api-pricing-protests-caused-reddit-to-crash-for-3-hours/">crashed Reddit for three hours</a>, and is scheduled to continue until June 14. Reddit CEO Steve Huffman, according to an internal memo reportedly viewed by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/13/23759559/reddit-internal-memo-api-pricing-changes-steve-huffman">The Verge </a>today, isn't <em>too</em> worried, though, since it hasn't hurt Reddit's pockets yet.</p>
<p>According to The Verge (where you can view the full memo), Huffman sent the note to employees on Monday afternoon. It starts by noting the "challenge" from the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/reddits-plan-to-kill-third-party-apps-sparks-widespread-protests/">Reddit API pricing protest</a>.</p>
<p>"We do anticipate many of [the subreddits] will come back by Wednesday, as many have said as much. While we knew this was coming, it is a challenge nevertheless, and we have our work cut out for us," the note reportedly says. "A number of Snoos [Reddit's nickname for employees] have been working around the clock, adapting to infrastructure strains, engaging with communities, and responding to the myriad of issues related to this blackout."</p>
<h2>This, too, shall pass</h2>
<p>Then, the note seemingly seeks to calm employee anxieties or fears around the protests by depicting the blackout as a temporary occurrence that hasn't yet impacted Reddit's finances:</p>
<blockquote><p>We have not seen any significant revenue impact so far and we will continue to monitor.</p>
<p>There’s a lot of noise with this one. Among the noisiest we’ve seen. Please know that our teams are on it, and like all blowups on Reddit, this one will pass as well.</p></blockquote>
<p>Some subreddits have said they will go dark indefinitely. As of this writing, 8,444 subreddits are protesting, according to the <a href="https://reddark.untone.uk/">Reddark counter</a>, which says 8,838 subreddits pledged to join.</p>
<p>Similar to how <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/02/cash-strapped-twitter-to-start-charging-developers-for-api-access-next-week/">Twitter was</a> accosted when it jacked up its API pricing in February, Reddit has been accused of corporate greed as it seeks to suddenly charge what some argue are exorbitant amounts for something that used to be free.</p>
<p>For its part, Reddit hasn't been shy about its desire to make money, especially considering many popular third-party Reddit apps don't run Reddit's ads, its biggest source of revenue.</p>
<p>"Reddit needs to be fairly paid to continue supporting high-usage third-party apps. Our pricing is based on usage levels that we measure to be comparable to our own costs," Reddit spokesperson Tim Rathschmidt <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/reddit-insists-on-being-fairly-paid-amid-api-price-protest-plans-layoffs/">said</a> in a statement to Bloomberg on June 6.</p>
<p>News of Reddit's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/reddit-files-us-ipo-2021-12-16/">initial public offering</a> has drawn further attention during this spectacle, as <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/reddit-aims-for-ipo-in-second-half-as-markets-gears-quietly-turn" rel="nofollow" data-ml-dynamic="true" data-ml-dynamic-type="sl" data-orig-url="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/reddit-aims-for-ipo-in-second-half-as-markets-gears-quietly-turn" data-ml-id="1" data-ml="true" data-xid="fr1686683604018cch" data-skimlinks-tracking="xid:fr1686683604018cch" data-uri="00826ae77eb876a974b820674d4a6284">The Information</a> in February reported that Reddit aims to go public in 2023. Additionally, there's a sense that Reddit is seeking greater control over its platform.</p>
<p>Huffman's memo reportedly said that the long-term solution to challenges brought on by the protests is to improve Reddit and noted "a few upcoming critical mod tool launches we need to nail."</p>
<p>Reddit recently started allowing <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/05/reddit-welcomes-nsfw-desktop-image-uploads-ahead-of-imgurs-ban/">NSFW image uploads</a> on its desktop app but will remove NSFW content from third-party apps with its API changes, attributing the move to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/06/09/reddit-ceo-doubles-down-on-attack-on-apollo-developer-in-drama-filled-ama/"> regulatory concerns</a>. Reddit has also refrained from offering any compromise that would see lower API fees for developers that run Reddit's ads.</p>
<p>Further, Reddit showed interest in growing the use of its apps when it experimented with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/help/comments/135tly1/comment/jim40zg/">blocking logged-in mobile browser access</a> earlier this year.</p>
<h2>Community consequences</h2>
<p>Reddit might not have seen any financial consequences yet. But its announced API fees, the revelation that those fees would cost it <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/05/reddits-api-pricing-results-in-shocking-20-million-a-year-bill-for-apollo/">$20 million a year</a> for one third-party app, and the backlash from other developers, users, and moderators have shaken the Reddit community. It's hard to quantify that impact, but a sense of community is why some people visit Reddit in the first place.</p>
<p>Huffman's note, according to The Verge, said:</p>
<blockquote><p>I am sorry to say this, but please be mindful of wearing Reddit gear in public. Some folks are really upset, and we don’t want you to be the object of their frustrations.</p></blockquote>
<p>In an active <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/reddit/comments/145bram/addressing_the_community_about_changes_to_our_api/" data-uri="0b7bd1abc9fc933f0aad7979e931e5bf">Q&amp;A</a> on Friday, someone asked Huffman if he was concerned "that Reddit has become increasingly profit-driven and less focused on community engagement," and his response didn't foster a sense of community either.</p>
<p>"We’ll continue to be profit-driven until profits arrive. Unlike some of the 3P apps, we are not profitable," Huffman <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/reddit/comments/145bram/comment/jnkd09c/?context=3" data-uri="2fae66acd3a7d27a8084f5a3f4add389">said.</a></p>
<p>In Monday's note, Huffman reportedly mentioned the planned closures of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/reddits-new-api-pricing-will-kill-off-apollo-on-june-30/">Apollo</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/redditisfun/comments/144gmfq/rif_will_shut_down_on_june_30_2023_in_response_to/">Reddit Is Fun</a>, "and a couple others," and said, "We are still in conversation with some of the others."</p>
<p>As some might have expected, the protests haven't yet brought any sign of Reddit relenting on its API pricing. The company has given accessibility-focused apps exemptions, though.</p>
<p>"In this whole saga, I don’t think I’ve seen Reddit offer to give an inch on any of the things," Apollo developer Christian Selig <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/13/23759180/reddit-protest-private-apollo-christian-selig-subreddit">told</a> The Vergecast podcast this week.</p>
<p><em>Advance Publications, which owns Ars Technica parent Condé Nast, is the largest shareholder in Reddit.</em></p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947571&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/06/reddit-ceo-assures-employees-that-api-protests-havent-hurt-revenue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>303</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alan Wake II preview: A waking nightmare</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947600</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/alan-wake-ii-preview-a-waking-nightmare/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ars Contributors]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 20:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alan Wake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alan wake 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remedy Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you afraid of the dark?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/aw2game-800x450.png" alt="I just wanted some toilet paper from the General Store... what the heck is that?!"/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/aw2game.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="675" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> I just wanted some toilet paper from the General Store... what the heck is that?! (credit: Remedy )</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Over a decade ago, the release of <i>Alan Wake </i>cemented Remedy Entertainment—then best-known for the <i>Max Payne </i>series—as the arbiter of mind-bending, original, and somewhat experimental experiences that blend traditional action-adventure gameplay with atmospheric environments and existential dread. Despite <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2010/05/a-carefully-designed-madness-ars-reviews-alan-wake/">a generally favorable critical response</a>, slow sales stifled the game’s franchise potential (launching the same week as <i>Red Dead Redemption </i>certainly did <i>Alan Wake </i>no favors). In the years since its 2010 release, however, <i>Alan Wake</i> has become something of a cult hit; a remastered version that dropped in 2021 renewed interest and paved the way for the sequel’s announcement at the Game Awards later that year.</p>
<p><i>Alan Wake II </i>has been a long time coming, but the 13 years in between games have given Remedy even more time to hone its game-development chops. At a hands-off, closed-door session during Summer Game Fest Play Days in Los Angeles, Remedy reps showed off the sequel’s progress with a live demo. According to Remedy, it’s the developer’s most ambitious game ever—and it shows.</p>
<h2>What is dead may never die</h2>
<p><i>Alan Wake II </i>picks up over a decade after where the original left off, but don’t expect to see the titular character in the early hours of the game. Instead, the opening chapters put players in the shoes of FBI Agent Saga Anderson, who has come to Bright Falls to investigate a series of ritual murders alongside partner Alex Casey (who shares a name with the protagonist from Alan’s in-game novel series and looks suspiciously like <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/max-payne-fans-want-sam-lakes-smushed-up-face-back-in-the-remake/">Max Payne</a>).</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/CauldronLake_PrimaryPath_Landscape-scaled.jpg"><img alt='Welcome to Cauldron Lake.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/CauldronLake_PrimaryPath_Landscape-640x240.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/CauldronLake_PrimaryPath_Landscape-1280x480.jpg 2x" alt='Welcome to Cauldron Lake.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/CauldronLake_PrimaryPath_Landscape-scaled.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Welcome to Cauldron Lake.</a> (credit: Remedy)</p></div>
<p>One of those sacrificial murders was none other than Agent Nightingale, whom fans will remember as the trigger-happy, typically inebriated ex-FBI agent from the first game. Of course, few things actually stay dead in<i> Alan Wake</i>, which is why Anderson and Casey have found themselves trudging through the woods tracking the rogue agent’s apparent footprints. Once again, the words found on scattered manuscript pages are coming true all around Agent Anderson, and she has discovered that light is her best defense against the shadowy figures that inhabit the darkness.</p>
<p>The search takes them to Cauldron Lake, a hotbed of paranormal activity where the line between fiction and reality becomes blurrier than a tabloid photo of Bigfoot. Even though the lake is quite literally a thing of nightmares, there’s something comforting about seeing it again. It’s just as atmospheric as ever; during the demo, the fog set in, rain began to fall, and crows cawed in the distance. It’s a gloomy setting, but strategic lighting and pops of color from the local fauna ensured that it wasn’t too difficult to see what was going on.</p>
<p><div class="image shortcode-img right medium"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cultist_lineup_01_a-1-scaled.jpg"><img alt='Just saying hi...'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cultist_lineup_01_a-1-300x426.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cultist_lineup_01_a-1-640x909.jpg 2x" alt='Just saying hi...' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cultist_lineup_01_a-1-scaled.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Just saying hi...</a> (credit: Remedy)</p></div><br />
A key difference from the first game is the options players are presented with. According to a Remedy representative, there are different paths a player can take, a refreshing change from the fairly linear <i>Alan Wake</i>. Once the titular character is unlocked, players can switch back and forth between Wake and Anderson. Their stories are told in parallel as a single campaign with a unified ending, but there’s no right or wrong order in which to tackle each chapter, Remedy says.</p>
<p>Combat, perhaps the weakest point in the first game, also looks like it has been significantly improved. It’s less frantic and more strategic; Anderson’s extensive FBI training has apparently given her the ability to steadily shine a flashlight and aim a gun at the same time. While ammo and supplies are still scarce, it’s easier to make every bullet count when the approach to combat is more thoughtful. It certainly looked more fluid in our hands-off demo, although it’s hard to say if that’s because of a new design philosophy or the Remedy player’s familiarity with the game.</p>
<div><a name='page-2'></a></div>
<h2>Have a heart</h2>
<p>Back in Cauldron Lake, Anderson and Casey have split up, with Anderson still pursuing Nightingale. According to the manuscript, Nightingale’s heart has disappeared from the morgue (of course it has) and she needs it for a ritual to follow him over to the “other side,” known as the Overlap. When Anderson needs a moment to look over evidence and think about how the clues work together, she goes to a space in her mind that Remedy is calling the Break Room. Here, we can examine everything we know so far, from the photos on the evidence wall to various character profiles and testimonials. By combining certain pieces of evidence, the player can uncover new insights that give a clearer picture of what’s next.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Mindplace_Wide_COMP-scaled.jpg"><img alt='Sort the clues in your mind&#039;s eye. Red string not required.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Mindplace_Wide_COMP-640x272.jpg" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Mindplace_Wide_COMP-1280x545.jpg 2x" alt='Sort the clues in your mind&#039;s eye. Red string not required.' ></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Mindplace_Wide_COMP-scaled.jpg"class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">Sort the clues in your mind's eye. Red string not required.</a> (credit: Remedy)</p></div>
<p>In Anderson’s case, this has led her to a freezer in the general store, where she finds Nightingale’s missing heart. Returning to a so-called witch’s hut from earlier in the demo—inside of which is a coffee thermos, which now acts as a save point instead of a collectible—she completes the gory ritual and opens up the Overlap. It’s a creepy place that makes it difficult to sort reality from imagination; as she wanders through looping environments (“like a nightmare,” she notes), she hears the voice of her child, though he’s several states away.</p>
<p>Once inside, she’s finally able to confront the shadowy version of Nightingale, though he ultimately disappears before she can finish him off. Instead, she finds someone else washed up on the shore of the lake: a very rugged-looking Alan Wake. He’s confused, and even more so after he introduces himself and Anderson gives him a chilling message—he’s been missing for 13 years (hey, just like a certain game with the same name).</p>
<h2>When writer’s block attacks!</h2>
<p>The gameplay demo ended on that note, but <i>Alan Wake II </i>continued to dominate my thoughts for quite some time afterward. Remedy appears to be leaning more fully into survival horror this time around, and there were some genuine spooks during the demo, including one that had the entire room shouting with surprise and following that up with some sheepish giggles. While some moments could definitely be defined as jump scares, they’re certainly not cheap or random, instead contributing to the overarching story.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"<iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Eeoz8Zbosus?start=0&wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>The Remedy reps also shed some light on other new features to expect when the sequel drops, like inventory expansions and upgrades. Aside from a cringe ex-wife joke from Alex Casey, there was nothing in this gameplay session to prevent me from being more excited than I already was for <i>Alan Wake II</i>. After 13 years, expectations are understandably high, and we’ll find out if Remedy can meet them when Alan Wake hits PS5, Xbox Series S/X, and the Epic Games Store.</p>
<p>Let’s hope releasing the same week as <i>Spider-Man 2 </i>doesn’t cause history to repeat itself.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947600&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/alan-wake-ii-preview-a-waking-nightmare/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For reasons no one can fathom, McDonald’s has released a new Game Boy Color game</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947557</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/for-reasons-no-one-can-fathom-mcdonalds-has-released-a-new-game-boy-color-game/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 20:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game boy color]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Krool Toys regularly develops new games for Nintendo's 25-year-old handheld.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/IMG_7519-800x600.jpg" alt="We couldn't get it on genuine hardware on short notice, but the game runs fine on the Analogue Pocket using a Game Boy Color FPGA core."/>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/IMG_7519.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1440" data-width="1920">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> We couldn't get it on genuine hardware on short notice, but the game runs fine on the Analogue Pocket using a Game Boy Color FPGA core. (credit: Andrew Cunningham)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name='page-1'></a></div>
<p>Infinite monkeys working at infinite typewriters would have trouble coming up with the sentence I am about to write: Fast food giant McDonald's has released a new retro-style game featuring Grimace, the purple milkshake blob. While it's clearly meant to be played in a browser on a phone or computer, it's also a fully working Game Boy Color game that you can download and play on the original hardware.</p>

<p><em>Grimace's Birthday </em>was developed by Krool Toys, a Brooklyn-based independent game studio and "creative engineering team" with <a href="https://www.complex.com/style/a/mike-destefano/krool-toys-video-games-lil-uzi-vert-playboi-carti">a history of creating playable Game Boy games</a> as unique PR for musicians and brands. The game assumes you're playing in an emulator via a browser window—you can play that version of the game <a href="https://grimacesbirthday.com/">here</a>—but we also got it running on an Analogue Pocket thanks to a Game Boy Color FPGA core and a downloadable ROM <a href="https://archive.org/details/grimaces-birthday">hosted on the Internet Archive</a>.</p>
<p>The game is so period-authentic that there's even a screen telling original monochrome Game Boy owners that the game "<a href="https://twitter.com/nickisonlinet/status/1668424701436100609?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">requires a color device to play</a>." Even on Game Boy hardware, it still makes references to people playing on "mobile devices,"</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt='Obviously we ran to play it on actual hardware as quickly as we could, but the game knows most people are going to encounter it in a browser via an emulator.'  src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/IMG_7518.jpg" alt='Obviously we ran to play it on actual hardware as quickly as we could, but the game knows most people are going to encounter it in a browser via an emulator.' ><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Obviously we ran to play it on actual hardware as quickly as we could, but the game knows most people are going to encounter it in a browser via an emulator. (credit: Andrew Cunningham)</p></div>
<p>The game involves simple 2D platforming and skateboarding, not unlike some sections of the Game Boy Color <em>Tony Hawk</em> games; Grimace needs to collect milkshakes and do sick stunts as he tries to track down other McDonaldland characters so he can party with them. It's short—there are only four levels and one bonus round, plus score attack and free-skate modes—but the pixel art is legitimately great, and the levels that are here are cleverly designed.</p>
<p>Indie developers have been <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/05/meet-the-developers-making-og-game-boy-games-in-2021/">embracing the Game Boy recently</a>, thanks to beginner-friendly tools like <a href="https://www.gbstudio.dev/">GB Studio</a>. As McDonald's promotions go, this one is only slightly stranger than the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/05/finally-you-can-play-tetris-on-a-giant-chicken-nugget/">officially licensed Tetris-McNugget</a> recently released by McDonald's China.</p>
<p>For those of you who aren't aware of deep McDonaldland lore, Grimace is a giant fuzzy purple blob who has been described in official materials as a "monster," a "taste bud," and "the embodiment of a milkshake." He was originally depicted as "<a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/EvilGrimaceOrigin.jpeg">The Evil Grimace</a>," a four-armed thief who stole milkshakes, but he lost the lower pair of arms, did a heel-face turn, and became a lovable doofus in subsequent ads.</p>
<p>Grimace faded from most McDonald's ads and marketing materials in the early 2010s (the McDonald's fan wiki says he "vanished from public life," which is a hilarious way to describe the quiet retirement of a secondary corporate mascot), but the company has trotted him and various Grimace-themed merchandise back out for a social media campaign to celebrate the character's anniversary.</p>
<p>McDonald's isn't the only company to pull off a retro-gaming-themed PR gambit today. Atari is also releasing a new game for the Atari 2600, an announcement that also served to drum up interest in its upcoming title <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/a-company-called-atari-is-releasing-a-brand-new-2600-cartridge-this-year/"><em>Mr. Run and Jump</em></a>. If Halliburton announces a new Sega Master System game about fracking in the next 24 hours, I'll know someone is messing with me.</p>

<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=1947557&comments=1">Read Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/for-reasons-no-one-can-fathom-mcdonalds-has-released-a-new-game-boy-color-game/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>